[MUSIC]
Stanford University,
斯坦福大学,
>> Welcome to Stanford CS193P, Developing Applications for
> >欢迎来到斯坦福CS193P,开发应用程序
iOS, Winter 2017,
iOS,2017年冬天,
This is lecture number 16,
这是16号讲
We have some miscellaneous topics today, all of which I
今天我们有一些各种各样的话题,所有的我
think might be interesting to you for your final projects,
认为可能是有趣的,你的最后一个项目,
We're gonna talk about alerts and
我们会谈论警报和
alert's cousin: action sheet,
警报的表亲:动作表单,
We'll talk about notifications,
我们将讨论通知,
that's the radio station model from our MVC,
这是电台从我们的MVC模型,
We'll talk about the application lifecycle: we
我们将讨论应用程序生命周期:我们
already talked about the lifecycle of view,
已经讨论过的生命周期来看,
but now we're gonna talk about the lifecycle of
但是现在我们要讨论的生命周期
the whole application,
整个应用程序,
And finally I'm gonna talk about persistence,
最后我要讲的持久性,
How do we store stuff so
我们商店的东西怎么样
that when our app launches it finds it and
当我们的应用程序启动它发现它
of course you already know a couple ways of doing that,
当然,你已经知道的几个方法做,
So I'm just gonna show you a couple others,
所以我要给你们几个,
Let's start with this alerts and action sheets business,
让我们从这开始警报和行动表业务,
These are "pop up and
这些都是“流行起来
ask the user a question" kind of user interfaces,
要求用户一种问题”的用户界面,
They're both just MVCs, alert and action sheet is just
他们都只是mvc,警报和动作表单是公正的
an MVC, and they're always presented modally or in
MVC,他们总是模式地展示或
a popover, which as we learned last time is basically modal,
弹窗,正如我们上次学基本上是模态的,
So alerts pop up in the middle of the screen,
所以警报出现在屏幕的中间,
they usually ask questions with only two answers,
他们通常只有两个答案,提问
Like yes or no, OK and Cancel,
像“是”或“否”,可以取消,
It is okay to have an alert I guess with just an OK button,
是好的一个警告我想只有一个OK按钮,
Usually you wanna maybe think of if there's a better way to
通常你想也许想到如果有更好的方法
present that information to the user than putting up
比将向用户显示信息
And then we start talking about having three answers
然后我们开始讨论有三个答案
an alert,
一个警告,
in alert,
在警报,
(A) you might wanna think about an action sheet,
(一)你可能想考虑一个动作表单,
which I'll talk about in a second,
我将讨论在第二个,
And (B) you just might wanna think about how am I getting
和(B)你可能想考虑我
the user in the situation where I'm asking them
用户的情况,我问他们
an emergency question,
一个紧急的问题,
and there's three different answers or
和有三个不同的答案
even more than three, that would really be interesting,
甚至超过三个,真的很有趣,
So, alerts are quite disruptive to the UI,
所以,警报非常破坏UI,
The user is happily using their user interface and
用户使用他们的用户界面和幸福
then bam, the whole screen goes grey and there's this
然后bam,整个屏幕是灰色的
little box in the middle and it's giving them some alert,
小盒子中间,给他们一些警告,
I saw a class forum post about using alert, and there was
我看见一个类论坛帖子关于使用警报,有
a great suggestion there from one of the TAs which is,
一个伟大的建议从一个助教的,
this is something you wanna read the Apple human interface
这是你想要看苹果的人机界面
guidelines about using alerts, when to use them,
指南使用警报、何时使用它们
what to say in alert, things like that,
在警报,说点什么,
And in fact, I recommend all of you read the human
事实上,我建议你读了所有的人
interface guidelines from Apple in general, so
界面指南从苹果一般
I'm gonna post that on the class forum, the link to that,
我要在类论坛帖子,链接,
And I'm actually going to hold you to it in
和我要抱着你
the UI part of the rubric in your final project,
UI的一部分标题在你最后的项目中,
So pay some close attention to that, Apple's done
所以一些密切关注,苹果的完成
a really good job of analyzing all the uses of the various UI
很好地分析所有的使用不同的UI
elements and kind of what works well, what doesn't work
元素和类型的什么是有效的,什么是行不通的
so well, and what's consistent between different things so,
很好,不同的东西之间的一致,
An alert can ask the user for a little bit of text,
警报可以要求用户输入一些文本,
This has been abused to
这是虐待
make like login screens out of alerts and things like that,
做像登录屏幕警报之类的东西,
It's pretty rare in my experience that you actually
它在我的经验,你真的很罕见
wanna ask for text in an alert, but I'll show you in
对文本警报想问,但我将向您展示
the demo today how to do it, but it's pretty unusual,
今天的演示怎么做,但它很不寻常,
And then there's action sheets,
然后有行动表,
now an action sheet does not gray out the whole screen and
现在动作表单没有灰色了整个屏幕
appear in a little box,
出现在一个小盒子,
instead on an iPhone it slides up from the bottom,
而不是在iPhone幻灯片从底部,
And on an iPad, it's always gonna pop over,
在iPad上,它总是会流行,
Now, an action sheet, I like to think of as
现在,动作表单,我喜欢的
a branching decision user interface element,
一个分支决策用户界面元素,
So a user has gotten to some point in the UI where you
所以用户已经在你的UI
simply can't really proceed without knowing
无法真的不知道
what the user wants to do,
用户想要做什么,
So for an example: maybe you want to include an image in
所以对于一个例子:也许你想要包括一个图像
something,
什么东西,
A contact, and it's the profile image, or
一个联系人,这个概要文件的形象,或
something like that,
类似的,
And do you want that image to come from the camera,
和你想要图片来自相机,
where it's gonna take a picture right now?
现在,它会拍照吗?
Or from the photo library, past photos you've taken?
或从照片库、过去的照片你了?
Or maybe from some collection view of clip art or something,
或者从某种集合视图的剪贴画,
avatars or whatever that you provide, so you've kind of got
头像什么的,你提供,所以你得到的
to go in one of these three directions so an active sheet
去其中的一个方向,所以一个活跃的表
might slide up from the bottom and say you know add photo,
可能会从底部滑上来,说你知道添加照片,
how do you wanna do it and you get these choices,
你想怎么做,你把这些选择,
And usually there's Cancel also which is I didn't mean to
通常也有取消我不是故意的
do that so cancel,
所以取消,
Action usually have more then two answers,
行动通常有超过两个答案,
It wouldn't be wrong necessarily to have an action
它不会是错的一定要有行动
sheet with only two answers but
但表只有两个答案
it just rarely does that circumstance arise,
只是很少出现这样的情况,
So what do these two things look like?
这两个东西看起来像什么?
This is what an action sheet looks like on an iPhone,
这是一个行动表看起来像在iPhone上,
You see how it slides up from the bottom there and it has
你看到它如何从底部那里幻灯片,
some choices in it and this is what an alert looks like,
一些选择,这是一个警告是什么样子,
It takes over the whole screen,
它接管整个屏幕,
This one happens to have a little text field in it,
这个恰好有一个文本字段,
with two choices there,
有两个选择,
So let's talk about the API,
所以让我们来谈谈API,
To make these work because it's the exact same API,
做这些工作,因为它是相同的API,
in fact it's the same MBC that does both of them,
事实上MBC是一样的,他们两人,
This is the API to create this view controller,
这是API创建这个视图控制器,
it's called a UI alert controller, and
它被称为一个UI警报控制器
it just has a title, which is that thing at the top,
它有一个标题,在顶部,
you see where it says redeploy Cassini,
你看到它重新部署卡西尼说,
In the picture on the left there, that's the title,
在左边的图片,标题,
And then message is just a short informational message
然后消息只是一个简短的信息消息
telling you what the heck is going on right now,
告诉你现在到底是怎么回事,
And then preferred style right there,
然后选择风格,
if you set that to action sheet you get an action sheet,
如果你设置动作表单动作表单,
If you set it to ,alert you're going to get an alert and
如果你把它,提醒你会得到一个警告
I'll show you that,
我将向您展示,
So the API for these is basically identical except for
所以对这些基本上是相同的除了API
this one little preferred style thing right there,
这个小喜欢的风格的东西,
So once you've created your alert, you wanna add buttons,
所以一旦你创建警报,你想添加按钮,
Now adding buttons to your alert or action sheet,
现在将按钮添加到你的警报或动作表单,
is done with add action,
完成添加操作,
And the argument to add action is a UI alert action object,
和添加操作的参数是一个UI警报操作对象,
And UIAlertAction is created with a title,
和创建UIAlertAction标题,
So that's the title of the button,
这是按钮的标题,
A style, and we'll talk about what all the styles,
风格,我们将讨论所有的风格,
the button styles are,
按钮样式,
And then a handler,
然后一个处理程序,
Now, this handler is just a closure that you provide,
现在,这个处理程序只是提供一个闭包,
This is the handler that's gonna get executed if that
这是处理程序的执行
button is pressed, so that's the model for
按钮被按下,这样的模型
alerts, it couldn't be simpler,
警报、不可能是简单的
So let's look in example one, we got Orbit Saturn right
让我们看一个例子,我们得到了土星轨道
there, see the title is Orbit Saturn,
看到标题是土星轨道,
The style, this style is called ,default,
的风格,这种风格,默认情况下,
So the default style, the text is gonna not be red, okay,
所以默认风格,文本会不会红,好吧,
it's gonna be whatever color you've got going on in
它会发生的任何颜色你有
your app there, usually blue,
你的应用,通常是蓝色的,
And then in my closure here, this orbits Saturn, so
然后在我关闭这里,这个轨道土星,所以
I'm gonna just go into orbit around Saturn,
我要进入环绕土星的轨道上,
That's Cassini's mission by the way, to go to orbit around
这是卡西尼号的使命,去绕
Saturn, so it's just going to do it, if I click that button,
土星,所以要这样做,如果我点击那个按钮,
And let's add another button,
让我们添加一个按钮,
this one's explore Titan, a moon out there,
这是探索泰坦,月亮,
This is a little bit outside, well it's inside Cassini's
这一点外,在卡西尼号的
mission but before we divert it,
任务在我们转移之前,
we wanna make sure we're gonna log in for example,
我们要确保我们会登录为例,
So here in my closure you see I've logged in,
所以在我关闭你看到我登录,
made sure I'm logged in before I go to type,
让我我去之前登录类型,
But it's the same kind of thing,
但这是同样的事情,
a default button right there,
一个默认按钮,
All right, so we've got those two default buttons,
好了,所以我们有这两个默认按钮,
the blue ones,
蓝色的,
How about that closeup of sun button,
特写镜头的阳光按钮,
Now if Cassini closed up to the sun,
现在,如果卡西尼号关闭了太阳,
it will be destroyed cuz it doesn't have enough
它将被破坏,因为它没有足够的
propulsion to escape the sun gravity well there,
推进摆脱太阳引力井,
So I made the style of this button be ,destructive,
所以我做了这个按钮的风格是破坏性的,
instead of ,default,
相反的,默认情况下,
And so ,destructive in an action sheet is gonna turn in
因此,表会在破坏性的行动
turn up red okay just so that the user knows "
出现红色好这样用户知道”
this one is probably something I should be carefully with",
这个可能是我应该仔细”,
And anytime you have a destructive action in your
并在你任何时候你有一个破坏性的行动
closure, you are probably going to want to confirm that
关闭,你可能会想确认
this really want do to that destructive action,
这真的要做破坏性的行动,
In this case, for example I'm gonna make them log in again
在这种情况下,例如我要让他们再次登录
or something like that,
之类的,
So that's destructive, and
这是破坏性的
then finally we've got the cancel button at the bottom,
最后我们有取消按钮在底部,
that's another type of button called Cancel style and
这是另一种类型的按钮叫风格和取消
you can see that it looks a little different right,
你可以看到它看起来有点不同吧,
it's kinda separated from the other buttons,
其他的纽扣有点分开,
It's not destructive in fact it's the opposite of
这不是破坏性的实际上是相反的
destructive, it gets you out of the problem,
破坏性的,它能让你的问题,
Of this action sheet,
这个动作表单,
to go back to wherever you were before,
回到无论你之前,
you're not really gonna redeploy Cassini,
你不是真的要重新部署“卡西尼”号,
And, but it is separated down there,
但它是分离,
It kind of gives it just a little bit of a highlight,
它给它一点点的一大亮点,
So I've added all my actions, I've got my buttons, and
我添加了我所有的行动,我有我的按钮,
now I want to make this action sheet appear on screen,
现在我想让这个动作表单出现在屏幕上,
And I do that with the normal method that
和我正常的方法
we talked about before, which is present,
我们之前讲过,这是礼物,
Remember, present is a view controller method that just
记住,现在只是一个视图控制器方法
presents the new controller using whatever modal
提出了新的控制器使用任何模态
presentation style is set in that view controller which by
演讲风格是由设置在视图控制器
default is modal,
默认是模态的,
So the action sheet slides at the bottom and
所以动作表单底部幻灯片
it's being modally presented,
它是模式地展现,
So that looks good on the iPhone but
这在iPhone上看起来不错,但
what about on the iPad,
在iPad上呢,
It would look terrible if that huge, if the thing was
它看起来可怕如果很大,如果是
all the way the width of the iPad and came up,
所有的iPad和出来的宽度,
Or if it was just tiny even in the middle it was just look
或者这只是小中间甚至只是看
out of place right there,
不合适的,
So of course on an iPad we put this action sheet in a pop
所以当然在iPad上我们把这个动作表单流行
And whatever button causes us to have to do this branching
不管按钮使我们必须这样去做分支
over,
结束了,
decision, that's the button that we're gonna have
的决定,这是我们要的按钮
the little arrow point to,
小箭头指向,
So how do we make that work?
那么,我们如何让工作吗?
we're presenting this alert using the modal style,
我们提出这个警报使用模态风格,
Because right now,
因为现在,
So it would come up modal on the iPad and
所以它会在iPad和模态
it would look terrible,
它看起来很糟糕,
So instead, we just have to go and
所以,我们必须去
change our action sheet MVC here to have a modal
改变我们的动作表单MVC模式
presentation style of pop over,
演讲风格的流行,
That means it's gonna still present modal but pop over,
这意味着它会仍然存在模态但流行,
Pop over is basically modal but
在基本上是模态但流行
different kind of presentation style,
不同的演讲风格,
And of course, when it pops up,
当然,当它出现时,
we want the little arrow to point at the redeploy
我们希望小箭头指向重新部署
button in my bar button item there,
按钮在工具栏按钮,
And so we're gonna do that with that same pop over
所以我们要做的,同样的流行
presentation controller that we set the delegate of last
表示控制器设置最后的代表
time so we could control the adaptation,
时间我们可以控制的适应,
Remember that from the demo?
记住,从演示?
And so we're gonna use that same popover presentation
所以我们要使用同样的弹出窗口
controller, and this time we're gonna set its bar
控制器,而这一次我们将设置它的酒吧
button item to be the redeploy bar button item, and
按钮重新部署工具栏按钮,和
the presentation popover presentation controller is
表示弹出窗口表示控制器
smart enough to know "I'm gonna make my little arrow
足够聪明,知道“我要让我的小箭头
point at that",
在项目”,
And as I said before with the presentation controller,
就像我之前说的显示控制器,
you could also have the little arrow point at an arbitrary
你也可以有小箭头指向任意
rect in a view or at a button,
在视图或矩形按钮,
That's it,
就是这样,
Now, what happens if we put this code in there, this alert
现在,如果我们把这段代码,这个警报
modes, modal presentation popover and we try and
模式,模式展示弹出窗口,我们试着
run, (by the way it should be lower-case p popover there),
运行,(顺便说一下应该小写p弹窗),
And we now try to run it back on the iPhone,
我们现在尝试运行在iPhone上,
what's it gonna look like there?
它会是什么样子?
It's gonna look exactly the same as it used to,
它会看起来一模一样,
And why is that?
这是为什么呢?
Adaptation, right?
适应,对吧?
It's gonna adapt to the fact that in this case we have
它会适应这样的事实,在这种情况下
a horizontally compact environment,
横向紧凑的环境中,
And it's not going to put it in a popover,
这并不是要把它放在一个弹出窗口,
So that's an automatic adaptation,
这是一个自动适应,
same thing we had before,
同样的事情之前,
So it'll look fine,
所以它会看起来很好,
So if you have an app that's universal,
如果你有一个普遍的应用,
you'll obviously put this little popover code
显然你会把这个弹窗代码
in right there and it'll look fine on your other device,
在这里,它将在您的其他设备上看起来挺好,
So that's the action sheet, what about alert?
这就是行动,警告呢?
Same thing exactly, basically we're just gonna say that
完全相同,基本上我们要这样说
the preferred style is alert in this case,
首选的风格是警报在这种情况下,
Here I'm gonna add a cancel button there,
在这里我要添加一个取消按钮,
I'm gonna add a login button,
我要添加一个登录按钮,
And I'm also gonna add a text field to this one,
我也会添加一个文本框,
so here's how I add a new text field,
这是我如何添加一个新的文本框,
I just say to the MVC, the alert MVC, addTextField,
我只是说MVC,警报MVC,addTextField,
Notice there's a little closure there that I can
注意这里有一个小,我可以关闭
include to configure that text field,
包括文本字段的配置,
Set the placeholder text,
设置占位符文本,
Actually, this looks like a password, so I'll probably
实际上,这看起来像一个密码,所以我可能会
want secure text turned on in there, things like that,
想要获得文本打开,类似这样的事情,
Probably would wanna use trailing closure syntax there
可能想使用后关闭语法
instead of using the whole thing, but
而不是使用整个事情,但是
I just wanted you to see the argument,
我只是想让你看到的论点,
it's called a configuration handler,
它被称为一个配置处理程序,
cuz that's what it does,
因为这就是它的作用,
It configures the text field,
它配置文本字段,
You can add more than one text field if you want,
您可以添加多个文本框,如果你想要的,
And then, the way you get the text out in your action,
然后,你得到的文本的方式在你的行动,
this is sort of the login button's action right there,
这是登录按钮的动作,
I'm gonna get the alert and ask for its text fields,
我要得到警报,要求它的文本字段,
which is an array of text fields,
这是一个文本字段的数组,
cuz I said you can have more than one text field,
因为我说你可以有不止一个文本字段,
I'm gonna get the first one out of there,
我要去第一个出来,
cuz I only have one,
因为我只有一个,
I could do at sub-zero and sub-one, whatever,
我可以做在零度以下,了点,,
depending on how many I have,
取决于有多少我,
And, then I'm gonna get the text out of it,
然后,我要得到的文本,
So now I have the text to other text, and so
所以现在我有文本与其他文本,所以
it's really easy,
很简单,
So let's have the TextField work,
我们有TextField工作,
Again with alert style we just present it modally,
再次提醒风格模式地展示它,
Now, in this case,
现在,在这种情况下,
we don't present this in a popover on the iPad,
我们不提供这个弹窗在iPad上,
So, it looks exactly the same as on the iPhone, a little box
所以,在iPhone上看起来一模一样,一个小盒子
in the middle, which is okay, it actually looks okay there,
在中间,这是好的,它实际上看起来好了,
So, nothing special in doing the alert case,
所以,做警告的情况下,没有什么特别的
So that's it, that's alerts and action sheets,
就是这样,警报和行动表,
I have a little demo,
我有一个小演示,
FaceIt here,
FaceIt这里,
Show you what this looks like,
告诉你这是什么样子,
Code this up,
这个代码,
Here we are in FaceIt, where we were before,
我们在FaceIt,我们之前,
And watch what I'm gonna do here,
看我要做什么,
So here I'm pressing my add button here to
所以这里我迫切的add按钮
do this nice editor MVC,
这样做不错的编辑MVC,
What happens here if I just hit done?
这里发生了什么如果我只是做了些什么?
No,
不,
It didn't work,
它不工作,
That's weird,
这是奇怪的,
I'll try again,
我会再试一次,
Let's try something like grin,
让我们尝试类似的笑容,
Squinting,
眯着眼,
Done,
完成了,
I just made this work,
我只是做了这个工作,
What's going on, Well, actually,
发生了什么,实际上,
this did work because look, it added one right here,
这个工作,因为看起来,它增加了一个,
It's just the name was blank,
的名字是空白的,
I went up here, I hit done and I didn't put a name,
我去,我完成了,我没有把一个名字,
So it comes back, this is really bad UI,
所以它回来,这是非常糟糕的UI,
because it "worked",
因为它“工作”,
But this is clear now what the user intends, for there to be
但这是清楚现在用户意图,有
blank lines there they can't even tell the difference
空行,他们甚至不能区分
between when there's something there or not,
之间有或没有时,
So really what we'd like is, when we click done right here,
所以我们希望的是,当我们点击完成,
we would like to put up an alert if you
我们想提出一个警告,如果你
didn't give a name,
没有给一个名字,
And maybe we'll even put a text field in and
也许我们甚至会把一个文本字段
let you type the name right there in the alert,
让你输入名字在警报,
Which is a little questionable UI but it's good for demo,
这是一个小问题UI但是演示,很好
So that's what we're gonna do,
这就是我们要做的,
So we're gonna have this done button right here,
所以我们要有这个完成按钮,
put up an alert if the name field is empty,
提出一个警告如果name字段为空,
So how do we do that?
那么我们该如何做呢?
Let's go over here to our editor MVC, the code here for
让我们去这里编辑MVC,代码在这里
our editor,
我们的编辑器,
Remember this code right here,
记住这里的代码,
Pretty simple,
很简单,
And what I'm gonna do, I wanna prevent that unwind segue,
我要做什么,我想阻止unwind,
that done unwind segue, I wanna prevent it from
unwind完成,我想阻止它
happening if the name is empty,
如果名称是空的,发生
So how do I prevent a segue?
那么我怎么阻止segue呢?
What's the method that I add?
我添加的方法是什么?
I hear whispers of it, yes I think I hear it,
我听到窃窃私语,是的,我想我听到它,
Should perform segue, remember that one,
应该执行segue,记住一个,
should perform segue so should perform segue with identifier,
应该执行segue应该执行segue标识符,
I'm gonna implement that,
我要实现,
And I'm just gonna say if the identifier is my unwind,
我只是想说如果标识符是我放松,
Does anyone remember what our identifier was?
有谁还记得我们的标识符是什么吗?
Let's go look it up so
我们去查一下
we can remind ourselves how we find it,
我们可以提醒我们如何找到它,
So, the it was, the unwind out of here,
所以,放松的,
Now, of course, we don't get to see our unwind segues
现在,当然,我们看不到unwind segue
as these little arrow lines,
这些小箭头线,
We had to go look in our document outline over here,
我们必须去看文档大纲,
And click on this MVC and look at the bottom right there,
点击这个MVC和看底部,
unwind segment, segue add Emotion, we called it,
放松,继续增加情感,我们叫它,
When we click on inspector, we'll see it, and
当我们点击检查器,我们会看到它,
we call it Add Emotion, that's the identifier for that segue,
我们叫它添加情感,segue的标识符,
So now we know what our segue's called,
所以现在我们知道segue叫做,
let's check it here,
让我们检查它,
So if the identifier is Add Emotion, and
如果标识符是添加情感和
if our name isEmpty, then we wanna return false,
如果我们的名字isEmpty,那么我们想返回false,
We do not want to allow to segue to happen if that's
我们不想让segue如果发生
empty, otherwise, what are we gonna return?
空的,否则,我们会返回什么呢?
Well, some people would mistakenly say return true,
嗯,有些人错误地认为返回true,
But you don't want to return true there,
但是你不想还真有,
you want to return super should perform segue,
你想返回超级应该执行segue,
Because you wanna give your super class a chance to,
因为你想给你的超类的机会,
it might have some segues, and you wanna give it a chance,
它可能有一些而已,你想给它一个机会,
To see if it want to allow this particular identifier,
是否想让这个特定的标识符,
So don't forget that, when you're overriding these things
所以别忘了,当你压倒一切的这些事情
don't return true there give your super class chance,
还真没有给你超类的机会,
So let's run this just to see what this did, we haven't done
让我们运行这个只是为了看看这个,我们还没有完成
any alert here obviously we're just preventing that done,
任何警告显然我们只是做预防,
Let's see even that works there we go,
让我们看看甚至工作好了,
Add, I'm not putting a name in here, done and turn off,
添加,我不会给一个名字在这里,完成关闭,
It didn't unwind, see but this would also be terrible UI,
它没有放松,看到这个UI也将是多么可怕,但
The user would think no, delete this app,
用户会认为没有,删除这个应用,
it doesn't work,
它不工作,
This is a broken app, I'm clicking this button here,
这是一个破碎的应用,我点击这个按钮,
It's not doing anything, forget it,
不做任何事,忘记它,
So you never wanna have a UI like that where you press
所以你永远不会想要有这样一个UI的新闻
a button and it just does nothing,
一个按钮,它就什么也不做,
that's really bad UI so do never do that,
这是非常糟糕的UI做从来没有这样做,
Instead we want to do an alert, so I'm gonna create
相反,我们要做一个警告,所以我要创造
a little function to put all this alert stuff in,
一个小函数把这些警报的东西,
private funk we'll call it handle unnamed face,
私人恐慌我们叫它处理未具名的脸,
And in there we'll do our alert business so
在那里我们会做业务,所以我们的警觉
I'm just gonna do it up here,
我要这样做,
I'm gonna handle this UnnamedFace,
我要处理这种UnnamedFace,
When I'm still gonna prevent this segway because I cannot
当我仍然要防止这个赛格威,因为我不能
do the segway when this name's empty,
赛格威这个名字是空的,什么时候
So I'm still gonna return false but I'm
所以我仍然要返回错误但我
gonna handle this UnnamedFace along the way here,
要处理这一路上UnnamedFace,
So here's handle unnamed face,
这是处理未具名的脸,
I want an alert easy alert = UIAlertController,
我想要一个警告容易警报= UIAlertController,
Here's the argumnet down here, title,
这是argumnet下面、标题
Let's have the title be something like Invalid Face
让我们标题是无效的
and the message, there's a lot of good stuff in the human
消息,有很多好东西的人
interface guidelines about message here,
接口指南关于消息,
You don't want to scold your user with these alert
你不想骂你的用户与这些警报
messages,
消息,
We want to be nice to them, so we just want
我们要善待他们,所以我们想要的
to kind of explain nicely what's going on like,
的很好地解释发生了什么,
We'll just have a face must have a name or
我们必须有一个名称或只有一个脸
something like that, maybe even that's a little harsh,
类似的,甚至有点苛刻,
But, we'll say, we don't want it to be too long but by
但是,我们会说,我们不希望它太长但
the same token we don't it to be, you know, terse and mean,
同样我们不,你知道,简洁,意思是,
So we're kind of somewhere in the middle, so
所以我们中间,所以
we'll say "a face must have a name",
我们会说“必须有一个名称“
And of course the style here, what is it?
当然这里的风格,它是什么?
Is it action sheet?
动作表单吗?
No, it's Alert style, so I've created an alert,
不,这是警告风格,所以我创建了一个警告,
This is a view controller this is returning, if I look at
这是一个视图控制器返回,如果我看
the type of alert right here, it's an alert controller,
类型的警报,警报控制器,
which is a UI view controller sub class,
这是一个用户界面视图控制器子类,
So I've got this nice thing,
所以我有这个好处,
let's just actually present this and see what happens,
实际上我们现在这个,看看会发生什么,
Let's go present Alert Animated,
让我们去提醒动画,
True, and we don't even need a completion handler,
真的,我们甚至不需要完成处理器,
we rarely need that completion handler by the way,
我们很少需要完成处理器,
You know, it just tells you, I've finished presenting this
你知道,它只是告诉你,我已经完成了这个
thing, if you want to do something you could,
的事情,如果你想做一些你可以,
Let's go back here,
让我们回到这里,
Go here, again, I'm not putting the name in, done,
到这里,再一次,我不会给这个名字,,
Well it's better,
这是更好,
My app is still completely broken though,
我的应用程序仍然是完全坏了,
because whoa, I got this modal view controller up,
因为哇,我得到这个模态视图控制器,
and there's no way to get rid of it,
没有办法摆脱它,
So my app is completely dead,
我的应用程序是完全死了,
The only way to get out of this,
唯一的办法,
is to literally kill the app,
是真的杀了这个应用程序,
So we don't want that,
所以我们不希望这样,
We never wanna have an alert with no buttons, obviously,
我们从来没有想有一个警告,没有按钮,显然,
So let's could give it a button, go over here,
让我们给它一个按钮,可以在这里,
To our alert, say alert,addAction remember is
警报,警告说,addAction记住
how we do that, and it's got a UIAlertAction and
我们如何做到这一点,和它有一个UIAlertAction吗
let's look at the arguments here for AlertAction,
让我们看看AlertAction的论点,
We got a title, so, I'm just gonna put an OK button,
我们有一个标题,所以,我要把一个OK按钮,
I just got finished telling you that you really don't
我刚刚结束了告诉你,你真的不要
wanna have alerts that'd only have one button,
想提醒,就只有一个按钮,
But this is a demo, so
但这是一个演示,所以
I'm just showing you how to add a button,
我只是向您展示如何添加一个按钮,
Here's an OK button,
这里有一个OK按钮,
The style on this one is a default,
这是一个默认的风格,
it's just a default button, it's not destructive, or
它只是一个默认按钮,这不是破坏性的,或
anything like that,
类似的,
One could argue this should almost be a cancel,
可能有人会说这几乎应该取消,
You're gonna see that I'm not gonna make it like a cancel
你会看到,我不会让它像一个取消
appear in a second and then the handler, we're not
出现在第二个,然后处理程序,我们没有
doing anything when we click OK, so now let's run it again,
做任何事情当我们单击OK,现在让我们再次运行它,
Oops, got a parenthesis there,
哦,有一个括号,
All right, let's run again,
好吧,让我们再次运行,
So here we go, we add,
所以我们开始吧,我们添加,
not putting a name, hit done, comes up invalid face,
不要把一个名字,点击完成,出现无效的脸,
A face must have a name, now I'm back here,
必须有一个名称,现在我回到这里,
This probably is minimally okay, right?
这可能是最低限度,对吧?
This is probably fine, the user would immediately know,
这可能是好,用户会立即知道,
I gotta give it a name and they go up here and
我要给它一个名字,他们在这里
give it a name and all would be well,
给它一个名字,一切就都好了,
But in order to show you text fields in alert, how about
但是为了显示你在警告文本字段,怎么样
when this comes up If give give them a text field,
当出现如果给给他们一个文本字段,
And let them enter a name, so they don't have to go back,
和让他们输入一个名字,所以他们没有回去,
enter a name, and click Done,
输入一个名称,然后单击完成,
They can just type the name right here, and click OK,
他们可以输入名称,并单击OK,
So how do we do that, well one thing in our alert,
所以我们如何做到这一点,有一件事在我们的警惕,
is that we would want to add a text field,
是我们想要添加一个文本框,
And in configuration handler we could figure this
我们可以算这和配置处理程序
to do whatever we want,
做我们想做的事,
we'll just say we won't have a configuration handler here,
我们就说我们不会有一个配置处理程序,
And then in our add action, when the user click OK,
然后我们加上行动,当用户单击OK时,
I'm gonna look in that text field,
我要看,文本字段,
get the text out of it and put it in my name field,
从中获得的文本,把它放进我的名字,
Remember that this handler gives you the action itself,
记住,这个处理程序给你行动本身,
the same alert action,
相同的预警行动,
It's kind of like if you had a delegate method, you'd get
这就像如果你有委托方法,你会得到
the thing that's delegating same kind of thing here,
授权的同样的事情,
This action here would be passed to you in the handler,
这个行动将传递给你的处理程序,
we don't need it though,
不过,我们不需要它
I'm just going to say that my self,name/text field,
我只想说我的自我,名称/文本框,
Its text equals the alerts
它的文本=警报
text fields, text fields,
文本字段、文本字段
text, actually I guess that's
文本,我猜的
all I needed to do there,
所有我需要做的,
Text field is an array,
文本框是一个数组,
So let's grab the first one out of there and get its text,
让我们抓住第一个出来,得到它的文本,
So this is fine except for look we're presenting this
这是好的除了我们展示这个样子
thing before we add the text field so that's not good,
之前我们添加文本框,这样不好,
So let's put this down here and try again,
让我们把这个,再试一次,
All right, go here, we're done,
好了,到这里,我们做的,
Now I have a text field in here,
现在我有一个文本字段,
we'll say Foo is the name we want, and we click Okay and
我们会说Foo是我们想要的名字,然后点击好
it puts Foo in their name text field, excellent,
它把Foo名称文本框,非常好,
However we're still making them go back and
然而我们仍然让他们回去
click done again, right?
再次点击完成,对吗?
Because now I can hit done and it works, got this in here,
因为现在我可以做的工作,这在这里,
But it would be really nice if I go into this
但它将会很好如果我进入这个
unnamed situation, and I typed something here, and
不愿透露姓名的情况下,我输入一些东西,
I click okay, if it would just do done automatically,
我点好,如果它会自动完成,
So does anyone remember how we perform a segue from code?
谁还记得我们从代码执行segue吗?
Cuz that's what we need to do,
因为这是我们需要做的,
we need to perform that unwind from our code,
我们从我们的代码需要执行,放松,
I'm gonna do it right here in my action handler,
在这里我要做在我的操作处理程序,
I'm just gonna say self,performSegue,
我只是想说自我,performSegue,
Exactly what you would think and the identifier?
你想和标识符?
It's that add emotion,
那就是增加情感,
which is the unwind segue and the sender,
unwind和发送者,
I don't really care who the sender is,
我不在乎谁是发送者,
I don't look at that in my prepare,
我不要看,我准备,
I don't need it for any reason,
我不需要任何理由,
That's all that's required there,
这是所有必需的,
It's a good chance for
这是一个很好的机会
me to show you perform segue, segueing from code,
我给你执行segue segue从代码中,
All done, here we go here,
全部完成,我们开始在这里,
Let's do our favorite one which is contentment right
让我们做我们最喜欢的一种满足感是正确的
there, so I didn't put the name in here,
在那里,所以我没有把名字放在这里,
Done, face must have a name, I'll say content,
做,必须有一个名称,我要说的内容,
We click Okay, it comes back,
我们点好了,回来,
Here it is, everybody understand "alert"?
在这里,每个人都理解“警戒”?
Alert's pretty straightforward to implement, action sheet is
警报实现很简单,动作表单
pretty much exactly the same way, no text fields,
几乎完全相同的方式,没有文本字段,
Obviously, in an action sheet, but
显然,在一个动作表单,但是
you just add more actions in that case,
在这种情况下,你只需要添加更多的行动
All right, back to our slides,
好了,回到我们的幻灯片,
The next thing we're gonna talk about Is notifications,
接下来我们要讨论的是通知,
Notifications are the radio station in that MVC
通知是MVC的电台
talk I gave right at the beginning of the quarter,
说我给在本季度的开始,
This is how we can, essentially,
这是我们如何,从本质上讲,
broadcast information blindly to other objects in our
广播信息盲目地在我们的其他对象
application and have them tune in if they're interested,
应用程序,让他们收听,如果他们感兴趣,
So how do we do this?
那么我们如何做呢?
The key to making notifications work is this
通知这是工作的关键
class called NotificationCenter,
类称为NotificationCenter,
So there is a default NotificationCenter,
这是一个默认的NotificationCenter,
which you get by accessing the static bar called default
你得到通过访问静态栏默认
on NotificationCenter,
NotificationCenter,
So you have NotificationCenter,default
NotificationCenter,违约
gives you this default notification center,
给你这个默认的通知中心,
And so you can do two things once you have a default
所以你可以做两件事一旦违约
notification center?
通知中心吗?
You can sign up to listen to radio broadcast or
你可以听广播或迹象
you can broadcast,
你可以播放,
Now who that you things you can do,
现在,你可以做的事情,
super simple API really they do nice job with this one,
超级简单的API真的与这个,他们做的不错
So first let's talk about how you sign up to listen,
首先让我们来谈谈如何签署听,
you wanna listen to a certain radio station,
你想听一个电台,
It's done with this method that you send to the default
用这种方法,你发送到默认
notification center called add observer,
通知中心添加观察,
So add observer means
所以添加观察者意味着
I'm listening to this radio station,
我在听这个电台,
And has three arguments, the first one for
有三个参数,第一个
name is the name of the radio station,
名字是电台的名称,
Now the type of that is NSNotification,name,
现在NSNotification的类型,名称,
And I'm gonna talk about that in a second, but
我将谈论这个,但是
that's just the name of radio station you what to listen to,
这是电台的名字你听什么,
The second argument is object: Any?
第二个参数是对象:吗?
That's basically, in a sense, the sender, the broadcaster,
基本上,在某种意义上,发件人,广播,
If you're only listen,
如果你只倾听,
interested in a radio station that's broadcast from
感兴趣的电台广播
a certain object, then you can put something there,
一个特定的对象,然后你可以把东西放在那里,
If you put nil there, it means anybody broadcasting on that
如果你把零,这意味着任何广播
radio station, I'm interested,
广播电台,我感兴趣,
So it's just a way of narrowing down,
所以它只是缩小的一种方式,
The radio stations are kind of weird in that you can have
奇怪的广播电台都是你
multiple people broadcasting on the same station,
多人广播在同一车站,
It's not like a real radio station where it's only one
它不像一个真正的广播电台的只有一个
radio station,
广播电台,
And then a third argument is a queue,
然后第三个参数是一个队列,
(it's actually four arguments, I guess),
(实际上是四个参数,我猜),
The third argument is a queue that you're gonna run
第三个参数是你要运行一个队列
this closure on,
这个闭包,
The fourth argument is a closure,
第四个参数是一个闭包,
So you sign up for this radio station and
你注册这个电台
when there are broadcasts this closure get to executed,
当有广播这个闭包去执行,
And that queue is
队列是
what queue that closure get to execute it on,
关闭队列得到执行,
If you say nil, by the way, for
如果你说nil,顺便说一下,
that queue you get executed on the same queue that
这个队列上执行相同的队列
the radio station broadcaster is broadcasting on, but
广播电台电视台,但是
very often here you're gonna be doing UI stuff,
经常在这,你会做UI的东西,
In which case, you wanna put operation,mainqueue here,
在这种情况下,你想把操作,mainqueue这里,
Operation,main, I think is, is what it was called,
我认为,操作,主要是它叫什么,
Cuz you obviously need to be on main queue
因为你显然需要主要队列上
to do any UI work,
UI做任何工作,
So inside this closure, you can see there's one
所以在这个闭包中,您可以看到有一个
argument which is notification,
论证的通知,
That is the broadcast packet,
广播包,
if you wanna think of it that was broadcast, and
如果你想把它播出,和
inside there there's a couple of things but the really
里面有很多但是真正的东西
important thing is something called the user info,
重要的是所谓的用户信息,
See that notification,userInfo,
看到通知,用户信息,
That's a dictionary that the broadcaster
这是一个电视台的字典
can put any information they want for
可以把他们想要的任何信息
people who are listening to this radio station,
人听这个电台,
We'll have some examples to see what kind of stuff people
我们会有一些什么样的人
put in their user info,
放在他们的用户信息,
So that's it, super straightforward,
就是这样,超级简单,
This is how you listen to a radio station,
这就是你听一个电台,
So let's see, before I show you an example of it,
我们看看,之前我给你一个例子,
let's talk about NSNotification,Name,
让我们来谈谈NSNotification、名称、
Its types like this which is really nice and
这样很好的,它的类型
swift in iOS 10 they really typed
斯威夫特在iOS 10他们真的类型
all of the things used to be just string, have been type so
使用的所有事情只是字符串,所以一直类型
you know what type of thing you're looking for here,
你知道什么类型的东西你正在寻找,
NSNotification,Name, what's really cool about that,
NSNotification,名字,很酷,
is if you go look at the documentation,
如果你去看文档,
for NSNotification,Name, you'll see all
NSNotification,名字,你会看到所有
of the radio stations that iOS will broadcast on,
iOS的广播电台播放,
And there's a lot of them,
有很多的,
But it's a great way to quickly learn what radio
但这是一个很好的方法来快速了解收音机
stations there are built into IOS,
站有内置IOS,
They're all static vars, these names of the radio stations
他们都是静态的var,这些名字的广播电台
are static vars in NSNOtification,Name,
是静态的var NSNOtification、名称、
Now you can create your own NSNotification,Name, because
现在,您可以创建自己的NSNotification,名字,因为
it's perfectly legal to create your own radio station, and
这是完全合法的创建自己的广播电台,和
broadcast if you want,
如果你愿意,广播
You just do that with the string initializer for
你只是这样的字符串初始化
the type NSNotification,Name,
NSNotification类型、名称、
NSNotification,Name, hopefully by now you're familiar after
NSNotification,名字,希望现在你熟悉后
reading your reading assignments and
读你的阅读作业
stuff, it's just a nested class, name,
东西,它只是一个嵌套类,名字,
it's a instruct or something inside NSNotification,
这是一个指示NSNotification内什么的,
That's why it's NSNotification,Name,
这就是为什么NSNotification、名称、
So I'll talk about broadcasting in a second,
所以我将讨论广播,
But first I wanna show you an example of listening,
但首先我要告诉你听的一个例子,
So here's a radio station, a system radio station called
这是一个广播电台,广播电台
UIContentSizeCategoryDidCha- nge,
UIContentSizeCategoryDidCha字,
you see it there under the forName,
你看到它在forName下,
And this if you go into your settings app on your phone and
这如果你进入应用在你的手机和你的设置
go under accessibility you'll see that there is a text size
破产可访问性你会发现有一个文本的大小
setting, looks like the thing on the right there,
设置,看起来像右边的东西,
where you can set the size of your text,
你在哪里可以设置文本的大小,
So when you get old like me you can make the text
所以当你变老喜欢我你可以使文本
a little bit bigger and
大一点
still see without having any reading glasses,
仍然看到没有任何阅读眼镜,
When your young like you you can make it really small so
当你像你这样的年轻你可以让它很小
you can get more text on screen,
你可以得到更多的文本在屏幕上,
So, when that changes though all the apps
所以,当改变尽管所有的应用程序
find out about it and each of them then locally broadcast on
发现和他们每个人在本地播放
this radio station,
这个电台,
Now, radio stations are only used for
现在,电台只用于
broadcasting inside your app,
广播在你的应用程序,
So the communication from iOS the operating system
所以从iOS操作系统通信
to the apps that this changed is happening some other way,
应用这其他方式正在发生改变,
You don't know what it is, it's behind the scenes,
你不知道它是什么,它是在幕后,
you don't care,
你不在乎,
But when an app finds out that this slider has changed,
但是当一个应用程序发现这个滑块已经改变,
it locally broadcasts on this radio station UI content size
在本地广播电台UI内容大小
category did change,
类别做了改变,
Because those little, that slider actually has, like,
因为那些小滑块有,,
detant marks on there, and it's not just, like,
detant痕迹,这不仅仅是,喜欢,
the point size or the font,
点大小或字体,
It's small, medium, large, extra large,
小型,中型,大型,额外的大,
extra extra large,
额外的超大,
So, as you slide that thing across,
所以,当你在幻灯片的事,
So if I want to hear about that change,
所以如果我想听到这一变化,
now why would I want to hear that this is changing?
为什么我想要听到的,这是改变?
I don't need to hear it from my fonts because
我不需要从我的字体,因为听到它
I'm being a good programmer and
我是一个优秀的程序员
I'm using the text styles in my UI,
我使用我的UI中的文本样式,
Remember when we went to the UI and
还记得我们去了UI和
we set the text style to be like body font or
我们设置了身体的字体或文本样式
headline font, or caption font, remember when we were
标题字体,标题字体,还记得我们
doing the little Tweet Twitter client there?
做小微博Twitter客户端吗?
So those will automatically get updated when this changes,
这将自动得到更新当这个变化,
But what if I have something else an icon or
但是,如果我有别的一个图标或
some other image that really wants to size itself depending
一些其他的图像本身真的想大小不同
on the surrounding text,
在周围的文本,
If the text gets really small maybe the icon wants to
如果文本也许图标想真的很小
if the text gets really big the icon wants to get bigger,
如果图标变得很大的文本想要变大,
get smaller,
变得越来越小,
So I might want to find out, so I find out by signing
所以我想找到答案,所以我找出签署
up to listen to this radio station with addObserver,
与addObserver听这个电台,
And here I'm saying I'm only
我说我只
interested if the UI application object sends it,
感兴趣如果UI应用程序对象发送它,
I can probably put nil there actually cuz I don't care who
我可以把零实际上因为我不在乎
sends this I know it's going to be the application object,
发送这我知道这将是应用程序对象,
but I don't really care,
但我不在乎,
And I am going to execute this on the main queue because
我要执行这个主队列,因为
I am going to do UI things for
我要做UI的东西
sure, in reaction to that size category changing,
当然,在反应大小类别发生变化,
And then inside my closure I look at the notification and
然后在我关闭我看通知
in the dictionary there I'm looking for the key called
在字典里有我要找的关键
UIContentSizeCategoryNewValue- Key,
UIContentSizeCategoryNewValue -键,
And I found out about that
我发现了这一点
by looking in the documentation under
通过在文档中
NSNotification,Name,UIContent- SizeCategoryDidChange,
NSNotification、名称、UIContent SizeCategoryDidChange,
And when I looked at that particular radio station,
当我看着那个特定的广播电台,
It said in the documentation,
在文档中,
hey, you can use UIContentSizeCategoryNewValu-
嘿,你可以使用UIContentSizeCategoryNewValu -
eKey to get out of the dictionary the size category,
eKey字典大小的类别,
In other words the position of that slider,
换句话说,滑块的位置,
And so an example what the value might be of that would
所以一个例子可能的价值
be UIContentSizeCategorySmall,
UIContentSizeCategorySmall,
So now I found out, and
现在我发现,
I'll find out every time that changes,
我会找到的每一次变化,
I'll get a broadcast and it'll tell me,
我将得到一个广播,它会告诉我,
Now, I didn't really talk about this, but
现在,我真的不谈论这个,但是
notice that addObserver, that notification,
请注意,addObserver通知,
default notification center method, it returned something,
默认的通知中心方法,它返回,
This thing observer, which is of type NS object protocol,
这个观察者,NS对象类型的协议,
Basically it's a cookie,
基本上这是一块饼干,
You don't what it is,
你不什么,
you don't know what type it is, all you use it for,
你不知道型号,你用它来,
is later when you're no longer interested in hearing about
以后当你不再感兴趣呢
this, you remove this observer,
这个,你把这个观察者,
That's, that's saying to the notification center,
这是,这是对通知中心说,
I don't wanna hear about this radio station anymore, so
我不想听到关于这个电台了,
don't send me anymore broadcasts,
不再给我广播,
Now it's really important to do that,
现在是非常重要的,
So usually we're going to do something UI-oriented
通常我们会做一些UI-oriented
like this,
像这样,
And then in view will disappear,
然后在视图将会消失,
we're gonna remove observer because it makes no sense to
我们将删除观察者,因为它毫无意义
listen to this radio station and adjust our icon sizes and
听这个电台和大小和调整我们的图标
stuff when we're not on screen,
东西时,我们不是在屏幕上,
Now of course, this might happen while we're off screen,
当然,这可能发生在我们离开屏幕,
So perhaps in our view did appear, or view will appear,
也许在我们看来确实出现,或视图将会出现,
we might want to adjust our icon sizes based on
我们想调整我们的图标大小的基础上
this content size category,
这个内容大小类别,
Which you can get that from the UI application,
你可以得到从UI应用程序,
you can just ask it what it is and it will tell you,
你可以问它是什么和它会告诉你,
you don't have to, have to get a radio station notification,
你不需要,必须得到一个电台通知,
to find out what it is,
找出它是什么,
That's an example of listening to a radio station,
这是听一个电台的一个例子,
Now what about sending on a radio station, broadcasting,
现在发送广播电台,广播,
That's super simple, as well,
这是超级简单,
You get that default notification center, and
你得到默认的通知中心,
you're gonna use the method post,
你会使用方法后,
Post takes the name of the radio station to post on,
文章需要广播电台发布的名称,
which again, you can invent your own if you want,
再次,你可以发明自己的如果你愿意的话,
The object, that's the sender, in case people might only be
的对象,发送方,以防人可能只有
interested in this being broadcast from certain people,
这从某些人广播感兴趣,
Usually, this would be self, that you would put there,
通常,这将是自我,你将在那里,
And then there's the user info,
还有用户信息,
That's that dictionary that you get to pass to them,
这就是你得到那本字典传给他们,
So, that's the same user info they're gonna get,
所以,这是他们会得到相同的用户信息,
So, as soon as you execute this post
所以,当你执行这篇文章
all listeners, all people who did addObserver, who
addObserver,所有听众,所有人
are listening on, for their closure to execute on the same
关闭监听,他们执行的一样吗
queue as your posting this on will immediately execute,
队列作为发布这将立即执行,
All the other ones, so
所有其他的,所以
if you're posting this off the main queue for
如果你发布了主队列
example and you're observers are all on the main queue,
例子,你观察人士都在主队列,
Their closures will just be put on the queue,
闭包就是放在队列中,
they'll be put on the main queue, and
他们会把主要的队列上,
they'll execute the next opportunity that they have,
他们将执行下一个机会,
So that's it, posting and posting to broadcasts on
就是这样,上传和发布广播
the radio station, by the way radio station that's just
电台,电台的
something I made up, nobody calls it that,
我了,没人管它叫
you're not gonna see that in the docs,
你不会看到在文档,
it's just a analogy for what's going on here,
这只是一个比喻,这是怎么回事
That's notifications,
的通知,
There's another kind of radio station model thing,
还有电台模型的另一种事,
which I'm not talking about, which is key value observing,
我并不是在谈论,键值观察,
And you might wanna look up in the docs as well,
你可能会想要查找的文档,
That's a way that you can sign up to find out if a var
这是一种你可以注册发现如果一个var
on some other object changes,
在其他对象的变化,
So, take a look at that if you might be interested in that,
所以,看一看,如果你可能会感兴趣,
The next topic here is the application life cycle,
这里的下一个主题是应用程序生命周期,
You know how we have a view life cycle,
你知道我们有一个生命周期,
we have an application one too and you get to find out as
我们也有一个应用程序,你可以找到
your application goes through its life cycle,
您的应用程序通过它的生命周期,
So first let me talk about the states that your application
首先让我谈谈您的应用程序的状态
can be in,
可以的,
It can be in really one of five conditions,
它可以在真正的五个条件,
One is the top not running,
一个是前未运行,
So that's, user has never,
所以,用户从来没有,
not run your app, obviously you're not running,
没有运行你的应用,显然你不运行,
Your code, there's no code executing in
您的代码,没有代码执行
any way related to your app,
任何方式与应用程序有关,
No one's touched on your icon or anything,
没有人提到了你的图标,
Then there's two foreground states
有前景的两个州
after your app starts running,
你的应用程序开始运行后,
One is called the inactive state,
一个叫做不活跃的状态,
In the inactive state, you don't get any events,
在非活动状态,你得不到任何的事件,
You can't draw any UI,
你不能得出任何UI,
You're just kind of like preparing to, to really run,
你只是有点像准备,真正运行,
You're not active,
你不主动,
You're not being shown on screen,
你没有被显示在屏幕上,
The user's not interacting with you,
用户不是与你交流,
The other one the other foreground state is active,
另一个另一个前景状态是活跃的,
now this is the normal state where you're getting
这是你要的正常状态
touch events, you're drawing on screen, you're interacting
触摸事件,你画在屏幕上,相互作用的
user perceives you as an active application,
积极应用程序用户感知,
Then there's also the background state,
然后还有背景状态,
Now the background state is even less running than
现在后台运行甚至低于状态
the foreground inactive state, in the background state you're
前台不活跃的状态,你在后台状态
clearly not on screen and not only are you not on screen and
显然不是在屏幕上,不仅会使你的屏幕上
interacting you're barely running in the background and
你几乎在后台运行,进行交互
your lifetime there is limited,
你的一生是有限的,
You're probably not gonna run for more than 30 seconds,
你可能不会超过30秒,
This is a transitory state between
这是一个暂时的状态之间
being in the foreground and
在前台
going to the next state I'm gonna talk about,
进入下一状态我要讲,
which is to be suspended,
暂停,
So, if you're suspended,
所以,如果你暂停,
no code in your application is running,
没有代码在您的应用程序正在运行,
You're still in memory, but
你仍然在内存中,但是
you're just sitting there not running,
你只是坐在那里不运行,
You get no cycles,
你没有得到周期,
Now, one thing you have to be, you have to kind of understand
现在,有一件事你必须,你必须理解
about how this life cycle works is that you transition
这个生命周期是如何工作的是你过渡
through these states in an orderly fashion,
通过这些州以有序的方式,
So when you launch, you go from not running,
所以当你启动,你从没有跑步,
to this foreground inactive state, to active,
这种前景不活跃的状态,活跃,
You always transition through inactive to get to active,
通过活动来活跃你总是过渡,
When some other app is switched to, someone launches
切换到其他应用程序时,有人发射
another app and you're the you were the active app, you go
另一个应用程序,你的积极应用,你走
from active back to inactive in the foreground briefly,
从活跃不活跃在前台,
then around down to background for up to 30 seconds or
然后大约为30秒或背景
so and then you get suspended where you don't run at all,
然后你会暂停,你别跑,
So you always transition through that flow to go
所以你总是过渡流去
from you're the active app to somebody else's
从你积极应用到别人的
the other deactive app,
其他不激活应用程序,
Now when you're in suspended state and
现在,当你在暂停状态
you get killed for whatever reason,
你杀了不管是什么原因,
You go straight to killed and no code of yours runs from
你直接死亡,没有你的代码运行
the time you're suspended, to the time you get killed,
时间你暂停,你被杀死的时候,
Why do you get killed?
你为什么被杀?
Well, maybe the user killed you, explicitly,
也许用户杀了你,明确,
Maybe you started using too much memory and
也许你开始使用太多内存和
the system killed you,
杀了你,
Maybe the phone's battery died, it got re-booted, for
也许手机电池死了,重启了,
some reason, whatever,
某些原因,无论如何,
So when you're in the suspended state,
所以当你在暂停状态,
you kind of have to be ready to just be killed,
你不得不准备就被杀死,
So you wouldn't want to have any unsaved data, or
所以你不想有任何未保存的数据,或
anything else going on in that state,
其他的国家,
that's why you get the background state,
这就是为什么你得到背景状态,
to kinda get ready for that,
有点准备,
Now, at each of these arrows, these orange arrows,
现在,在每一个箭头,这些橙色箭头,
you get a message sent to your application delegate,
你得到一个消息发送到应用程序委托,
So far, we've only used the application
到目前为止,我们只使用应用程序
delegate to have our little core data stuff in there,
委托我们的小核心数据的东西在里面,
But there's a bunch of methods in there,
但是有很多方法,
You've seen them every time you look and you had delegate,
你看过他们每次你看,你有委托,
And we're gonna talk about what they all do and
我们要谈论什么都做
when they're all called,
当他们都是调用时,
So the first one in your app delegate is called application
首先在应用程序委托调用的应用程序
didFinishLaunchingWithOptions,
There's also
也有
a willFinishLaunchingWithOpti- ons,
willFinishLaunchingWithOpti——国家统计局,
And it gives you this dictionary,
这本字典给你,
And the dictionary,
和字典,
the keys are UIApplicationLaunchOptionsKey,
键是UIApplicationLaunchOptionsKey,
which you can look in the documentation for that symbol,
你可以在文档中寻找,象征,
And you'll find all the various things that can appear
,你会发现各种可能出现的事情
in this dictionary,
在这本字典,
And the values depend on what the key is,
和的值取决于什么是关键,
By the way, all of these app delegate methods,
顺便说一下,所有的这些应用程序委托方法,
you can also get by listening to this radio stations,
你也可以通过听这个广播电台,
So the radio station for
因此,广播电台
this one is the UIApplicationDidFinishLauching
这一个是UIApplicationDidFinishLauching
radio station and it's notification ,name,that If you
广播电台通知,名字,如果你
listen to that you'll get, and you do add observer,
你会听,你添加的观察者,
you'll get your closer called when did launch finish
你会得到你叫什么时候启动完成
launching happens, so you don't have to put it in your
启动发生,所以你不必把它放在你的
app delegate you could put it in other places other code,
应用委托你可以把它放在其他地方其他代码,
What happens here in this DidFinishLaunchWithOptions
发生了什么在这个DidFinishLaunchWithOptions
what why does it get called things like that,
为什么它被调用,
why do you have this dictionary?
为什么你有这本字典吗?
Well, obviously when you normally launch, this gets
显然,正常启动时,这个会
called, the dictionary doesn't have anything in it,
调用时,字典没有任何关系,
Because you just got launch normally,
因为你刚刚启动正常,
the user clicked on your icon and launched,
用户点击图标和启动,
But there are a lot of other ways for
但是有很多其他的方法
you to get launch to buy the system,
你推出购买系统,
And when those other ways happen,
当其他方式发生,
then you're gonna have this dictionary to tell you why,
那么你会有这本字典告诉你为什么,
and give you the information you need,
和给你你需要的信息,
So one thing, for example,
举例来说,这样一件事
is if your application opens a certain kind of document,
如果您的应用程序打开一个特定类型的文档,
let's say you're a PDF viewer and you know how to open PDF
假设你是一个PDF查看器,你知道如何打开PDF
files and you've registered that with the system,
与系统文件和你注册,
Then if someone in some other app says, open this PDF,
然后说如果有人在其他一些应用程序,打开这个PDF,
the system's gonna launch you,
系统会启动你,
And when it launches you, in the dictionary right there
当它启动,在字典里
is gonna be that URL with some key,
将该URL与一些关键
It's telling you to open it,
它告诉你打开它,
And so that's an example, another one is,
这就是一个例子,另一个是,
you have set up, you can set up with core location,
你有设置,您可以设置核心位置,
I didn't get to talk about core location this quarter,
我没有谈论本季度核心位置,
but you can set up a core location mechanism, whereby,
但是你可以建立一个核心位置的机制,即,
if you go by someplace in the world, the dry cleaner,
如果你去世界上的某个地方,干洗店,
just the canonical example,
典型的例子,
when you walk by the dry cleaner, your app will launch,
当你走到干洗店,应用程序将启动,
So you could set it up and if that happens again,
所以你可以设置它,如果出现这种情况,
this dictionary will say, hey I launched you because you
这本词典会说,嘿,我了你,因为你
went to one of your registered locations and
去你的一个位置和注册
here it is when you worked,
这是你工作的时候,
You can also do it for continuing activities,
也可以继续活动,
I don't know if you guys know about this feature,
我不知道你们是否知道这个特性,
it's kind of a nice feature,
这是一种不错的功能,
You start browsing something on your phone, and
你开始浏览的东西在你的手机上
then you switch over to your iPad,
然后切换到你的iPad,
You can continue browsing from exactly where you were,
你从哪里你可以继续浏览,
So you might get launched to do that,
所以你可能会推出,
to continue doing what you were doing,
继续做你所做,
If you get a push notification,
如果你得到一个通知,
we didn't really talk about notifications much except for
我们没有谈论通知除外
in the cloud kit section, I hope you,
云中的设备部分,我希望你,
how many of you saw the cloud kit Friday section?
你们中有多少人看到云工具包周五部分?
It's only a few of you, it's worth going back and looking
只有少数的你,值得去看
at just to see notifications and push notifications,
在看到通知和推送通知,
But if you get a push notification sent to you and
但如果你得到一个推送通知发送给你
your app's not running,
你的应用程序不运行,
it may get launched to handle that thing,
它可能会推出去处理那件事,
Or if you have some Bluetooth device that you connect with,
或者如果你有一些你连接的蓝牙设备,
it, it gets in range and it gets launched,
它,它就在范围和启动,
So there's a lot of reasons your
所以你有很多的原因
application might get launched,
应用程序可能会启动,
And when it does,
当这样的事发生了,
that dictionary's going to have the information
那本字典会有信息
related to that particular launch,
相关的特定的发射,
Now I'm gonna warn you of something, when you're doing
现在我要警告你,当你做的事情
your final project, you're gonna be searching on
你最后的项目,你要搜索
the Internet all the time to find ways to do things,
所有的时间上网寻找方法,
And you might run across really old posts, which you
你可能会遇到非常古老的帖子,你
can often tell because they're in Objective C versus Swift,
通常可以告诉因为他们在Objective - C和迅速,
But if you ever see a post where
但是如果你看到一个帖子
someone in their application did finish launching with
有人在他们的应用程序并完成启动
options is like saying UI split view controller init,
就好比说UI分割视图控制器初始化选项,
or navigation init,
或导航初始化,
And they're building their UI in code right there,
他们正在构建UI的代码,
that's pre-story board code,
这是pre-story板代码,
we do that stuff in the story board now,
我们现在做的东西在故事板,
The times that we build any UI in application did finish
《纽约时报》,我们构建任何UI应用程序完成
launching, 0,001% of the time,
启动,0001%的时间,
So I just wanna make sure you don't get confused by that,
所以我只是想确保你不感到困惑,
So this little delegate method is sent with that arrow
所以这个小箭头委托方法发送
right there,
在这里,
You see the arrow that's down there?
你看到下面的箭头吗?
So that's the arrow where you go from not running
这是箭,你从没有运行
into being inactive,
是不活跃的,
So you're running, you can do stuff, but
所以你跑步,你可以做的东西,但是
you're not on screen,
你不是在屏幕上,
So in ApplicationDidFinishLaunching
所以在ApplicationDidFinishLaunching
with options, you could be building your UI, but
选项,您可以构建UI,但是
you can't put it on screen yet,
你不能把它放在屏幕上,
I mean, it won't appear on screen
我的意思是,它不会出现在屏幕上
cuz you're still inactive,
因为你还不活跃,
Now I wanna talk briefly about an opposite
现在我想谈谈一个相反
arrow there that can go into the inactive state,
箭头,可以进入不活动状态,
You can get into inactive from running, but
您可以从运行进入不活动,但是
you can also get inactive when you were running,
你也可以活动你跑步时,
And things happen, like you switch to another app, other
像你这样的事情发生,切换到另一个应用程序,其他
things can happen that cause you to go back to the inactive
事情会发生让你回到不活跃
state, where you no longer can do UI,
状态,你不再能做UI,
This transition, which is the WillResignActive transition,
这种转变,WillResignActive过渡,
you want to think of that as the pause button,
你想暂停按钮,
This is where your app wants to pause,
这就是你的应用要暂停,
So if we were doing an asteroids app,
如果我们做一个小行星应用,
I'd want to stop all of my asteroids,
我想要停止我所有的小行星,
remember what their velocities were,
记住他们的速度,
And be in a pause state,
处于暂停状态,
And then I'll show you what I'm gonna
然后我会告诉你我要什么
unpause in a second here,
unpause在第二个,
Then bring it all back,
然后把它回来,
So this is pause, I like to think of this one as pause,
这是暂停,我想这一停顿,
you're going from being the active app where your UI's
你要从活动应用程序UI的
working to this inactive state,
努力这种不活跃的状态,
You're still in the foreground,
你仍然在前台,
Now what causes this to happen?
是什么原因导致这种情况发生呢?
A phone call comes in, when a phone call comes in,
一个电话进来,当一个电话进来,
your app kind of is in the background,
你的应用程序在后台的,
It's, you can't do any UI,
你不能做任何UI,
it gets no events because the person's talking on the phone,
它没有事件,因为人的讲电话,
But as soon as their phone call ends,
但一旦他们电话结束,
you go back to being the active state,
你回到活动状态,
you never went into the background,
你永远不会走进后台,
You just were foreground inactive,
你只是前景不活跃,
Or you'll pass through this arrow
或者你会经过这个箭头
on your way to the background,
在你的背景,
Someone did click on another app, and so
有人点击另一个应用程序,因此
you're transitioning back here, still wanna pause,
你过渡回到这里,还想暂停,
And then you're gonna go to the background, gonna clean up
然后你要去后台,要清理
some more cuz you might get terminated later,
一些因为你可能会终止后,
But here, you still, i's worth pausing as you pass
但在这里,你还在,我值得你通过暂停
through here, so tha's what the resign state is,
在这里,所以那是辞职的状态是什么,
This other arrow going in the other direction,
另一箭向着另一个方向,
this is when your app really starts up,
这是当你的应用程序启动时,
So this is when your UI is available,
这是当你的UI是可用的,
Here's where you wanna unpause,
在这里你想unpause,
If you have paused, then here's where you unpause,
如果你有停顿了一下,然后在这里你unpause,
is in this DidBecomeActive,
在这个DidBecomeActive,
Because you're gonna pass through this on your way back
因为你要通过这回来的路上
from being in the background or when the phone call ends,
从背景中或在电话结束时,
then you're gonna go active,
然后你要活跃,
So this is the unpause,
这是unpause,
Now you only unpause obviously if you're paused,
现在你只有unpause显然如果你停了下来,
You never paused, then there's no unpause here,
你从不停顿了一下,然后这里没有unpause,
This little arrow down in the corner,
这个小箭头在角落里,
this is the DidEnterBackground state,
这是DidEnterBackground状态,
this is where you wanna batten down the hatches,
这就是你想未雨绸缪,
You wanna save any unsaved information,
你想保存任何未保存的信息,
you've already paused probably,
你可能已经停了下来,
because you went up through the active, can't get there
因为你通过主动上去,不能到达那里
from active, unless you went through the inactive pause,
从活跃,除非你经历活动暂停,
See how the arrows go there, so
看箭头去那里
here's where you wanna save things,
在这里你要保存的东西,
You wanna get yourself in the state, you got about 30
你想让自己的国家,你有大约30
seconds to do it where you could be killed and
秒,你可以杀,
usually would lose any data or anything,
通常将失去任何数据,
This is also a good place maybe to
也许这也是一个好地方
save your state a little bit, so if you did get killed and
保存你的状态一点,所以如果你做得到死亡,
you got run again,
你有再次运行,
you could start up exactly where you were,
你可以启动你是哪里,
And there's actually certain infrastructure in
和有一定的基础设施
UI application, which I'll mention in a second,
UI应用程序,我将提到,
to do that,
要做到这一点,
So this is the batten down the hatches area right here,
这是未雨绸缪的区域,
the transition,
的转变,
When you come back out of the background, so
当你回来的背景,所以
you were in the background or
你是在后台
suspended, when you come back out, you're gonna get this
暂停了,当你回来,你会得到这个
ApplicationWillEnterForegro- und,
ApplicationWillEnterForegro - und,
So, that's the thing that says, you will, back up,
这是说的东西,你会回来,
this is where you can unbatten down the hatches if you
在这里你可以unbatten如果你做准备
wanna open some files that you had closed or
想要一些文件,你已经关闭或打开
something like that, you can do that here,
这样,你可以在这里,
Have you got that?
你明白我的意思吗?
So these are the transitions you make through the lifetime
这是转换你一生
of your application,
你的应用程序中,
The ApplicationDelegate is involved in a lot of other
ApplicationDelegate参与很多其他的
things as well besides just the lifecycle,
东西除了生命周期,
For example, state restoration, this is the thing
例如,状态恢复,这是一件事
I was telling you be, just moments ago, where you can
我告诉你,就在片刻前,你可以
save your state, so that when you launch again, yo're in
拯救你的国家,所以,当你再次启动,哟
exactly the same state on the same view controller,
完全相同的状态在同一视图控制器,
Maybe even your first responder is the same blinking
甚至你的第一反应都是一样的闪烁
cursor and the same text field or whatever,
光标和相同的文本字段,
you can save all that, there's a whole mechanism for
你可以保存所有,有一个完整的机制
doing that,
这样做,
You can take a look at it if you want,
你可以看看它如果你想,
might be a good thing to get a rubric point out of in there,
可能是一件好事的标题指出,
Also data protection, so the data on your phone
数据保护,数据在你的手机上
is protected by default when you're in the locked state,
默认情况下保护处于锁定状态时,
Your phone is locked,
你的手机被锁定,
Then all the phone, data on it is encrypted, so
然后所有的电话,数据是加密的,因此
even if someone broke into the phone somehow and
即使有人闯入了电话不知怎么的和
got the data out of the static ram,
有静态ram的数据,
It would all be encrypted, so it'll be useless anyway,
这都是加密的,所以它会是无用的,
So the AppDelegate can tell you when
所以在AppDelegate可以告诉你什么时候
data becomes unencrypted and available for use,
数据加密和可供使用,
In other words, unlock, the screen has been unlocked, or
换句话说,解锁,解锁屏幕,或
when it goes back to being locked,
当它回到被锁,
You can open URLs in other apps,
你可以打开网址在其他应用程序,
There's a method, I think you wanted the extra credit items,
有一个方法,我认为你想要额外的信贷项目,
Or maybe we've even made it as
也许我们甚至使它
part of the required task of one,
必需的任务的一部分,
So you probably know how to do that,
所以你可能知道怎么做,
This is the other way around,
这是相反的,
This is someone's asking you to open a URL in AppDelegate,
这是别人问你在AppDelegate开设一个URL,
So this is: you'll get this message,
这是:你会得到这条消息,
your AppDelegate saying, hey, this, some other app wants you
你AppDelegate说,嘿,这一点,其他应用程序希望你
to open this URL, and you can go do it,
打开这个网址,你可以去做,
Similar to if you got launched,
如果你有类似启动,
if you didn't get launched to it,
如果你没有得到了它,
because if you got launched to it,
因为如果你有了它,
it's gonna be in that dictionary, but otherwise,
它会在那本字典,但除此之外,
you'll get this method,
你会得到这个方法,
And there's also a whole mechanism for
还有一个机制
background fetching,
背景提取,
Sometimes you might have an app, it's a social media app,
有时你可能有一个应用程序,这是一个社会媒体应用,
And you wanna have up to date information for
和你想要的最新信息
the user at all times, so that if they launch, they're seeing
用户在任何时候,如果他们发射,看
the latest posts on your Facebook page, or whatever,
最新的文章在你的Facebook页面上,等等,
And to do that, you can set up this background fetching,
为此,您可以设置这个后台取回,
Now, the background fetching is not happening once a minute
现在,后台抓取一分钟没有发生一次
or anything like that,
或类似的东西,
It's happening, you know,
它发生,你知道,
occasionally in the background, and
偶尔在后台,
if you try to do too much, the system,
如果你试图做太多,系统,
will get upset at you and stop doing, scheduling you so much,
会难过在你停止做,安排你,
But what happens here in the background fetching is, you
但是这里发生了什么在后台抓取,你
move from the suspended state into the background state for
从挂起状态到背景状态
30 seconds or less, usually,
30秒或更少,通常,
And you go you get to go fetch on the network or
和你走在网络或去取回
get your latest information, and
把你的最新信息
then you go back to suspended,
然后你回到暂停,
So that way if you go suspended background,
所以,如果你暂停了背景,
foreground active really quick, you got the data,
前台主动很快,你得到数据,
There's a few other things, but that's mostly what
有一些其他的事情,但那是什么
the ApplicationDelegate is all about,
ApplicationDelegate就是,
Now application delegate of course has to be a delegate
现在应用程序委托当然必须是一个委托
of some object,
的对象,
And it's a delegate of UI application,
这是一个UI应用程序的委托,
So UI application is a class there's only a single instance
所以UI应用程序是一个类只有一个实例
that you ever have in your app,
你曾经在你的应用程序,
You get it by saying UIApplication,shared and
你得到UIApplication说,和共享
it manages all the global behavior,
它管理的全球行为,
Which sounds like, wow this is really important object,
这听起来像,哇,这是非常重要的对象,
But actually it's not that important,
但实际上并不是那么重要,
You almost never interact with UIApplication, because it
你几乎从不UIApplication相互作用,因为它
delegates all the interesting things to its app delegates,
代表应用程序代表,所有的有趣的事情
But there are a few things that you can do in
但有几件事你可以做
UIApplication,
For example, here's where you can open URL in another app
例如,你可以在另一个应用程序打开URL
you can register to receive push notifications here,
你可以在这里注册接收推送通知,
Push notifications your app will not get
推送通知应用程序将不会得到
unless you call this registerForRemoteNotifications
除非你称之为registerForRemoteNotifications
in UIApplication,
UIApplication在,
By the way, notifications, push notifications and
顺便说一下,通知,推送通知
local notifications have been unified in iOS 10 to this UN
当地通知联合国统一在iOS 10
notifications framework,
通知框架,
A local notification, a push notification you probably know
本地通知推送式通知你可能知道
what this is that's when some server send you
这是什么这是当某些服务器发送你
some information like in the cloud kit case where it's
一些信息像云中的装备情况
telling you hey some data changed in your data base,
告诉你嗨一些数据改变了在你的数据库,
But local notification are kind of cool as well,
但当地通知也挺酷的,
You can set up local notification that will fire at
您可以设置本地通知开火
a certain time,
一个特定的时间,
That's how a calendar app reminds you when you have
这是一个日历应用程序提醒你当你有
a particular appointment or rather it's using local
一个特定的约会或者使用本地
notifications and you schedule them for a certain time,
通知你安排一定的时间,
I think you can also do local notifications for location
我认为你也可以做局部地点的通知
changes, and you get near the dry cleaner or whatever,
变化,得到附近的干洗店之类的,
So local notifications,
所以当地的通知,
put push notifications are unified in iOS 10 and
将统一在iOS 10和推送通知
it's not part of UIApplication it's this other framework,
这不是UIApplication的其他框架的一部分,
Unfortunately I didn't have time to go over that,
不幸的是我没有时间复习,
By the way also local notifications is different
顺便也当地通知是不同的
from NSnotification, or just notification,
从NSnotification,或者只是通知,
Notification is that radio station thing,
通知是电台的事情,
local notification, and push notification are the, this
当地通知,和推送通知
other mechanism for notifying the user which is actually
实际上其他机制来通知用户
completely different not related to each other at all,
完全不同与彼此无关,
In application you can also set the fetching interval for
在应用程序还可以设置抓取区间
that background fetching thing I talked about,
这一背景下抓取东西我谈到,
If you get into the background and
如果你进入后台
you need more time, because 30 seconds is not enough,
你需要更多的时间,因为30秒是不够的,
Something is blocking or you need to get something from
什么是阻止或者需要得到一些东西
the network and you want some more time,
网络,你想要一些更多的时间,
You can ask for more time by asking the UI application
你可以要求更多的时间通过询问UI应用程序
object to begin a background task,
对象开始一个后台任务,
Now, again, you can't abuse this,
现在,你不能滥用,
If you keep asking for more and more time, and
如果你继续要求更多和更多的时间,和
you're trying to run for ten minutes,
你想跑了十分钟,
eventually the system's gonna say, that's enough,
最终系统的会说,这就够了,
This is for, just exceptional circumstances where,
这是特殊情况,
"argh, I need another minute please",
“啊,我需要一分钟请”,
Can I have some more time?
我可以有更多的时间吗?
And it'll give it to you as long as you don't abuse it,
它会给你只要你不滥用它,
The little spinner in the upper left hand corner of your
的小转轮的左上角
device, okay, that spins,
好的设备,旋转,
Have you ever seen that thing spinning when you're doing
你见过那个东西旋转,当你在做什么
something on the network?
网络上的东西吗?
You can control that, you can turn it on and
你可以控制,你可以打开它
off with this bool in UIApplication,
UIApplication这bool,
You can also find out a lot of information like remember that
你也可以找到很多信息就像记住
category sizer, the little slider text size slider,
类别筛选器,小滑块滑块文字大小,
You can find out what the preferred content slide
您可以找出首选内容
category currently is,
类别目前,
You can find out how much time you got remaining
你可以找到你剩下多少时间
on your background, sitting in the background,
在你的背景,坐在后台,
You can also find which state you're in,
你还可以找到哪个州你在,
foreground inactive, foreground active background,
前景前景不活跃,活跃的背景下,
You can find out which of those states you're in,
你可以找到哪些州你在,
So you're application's a little bit of a clearing
所以你应用程序的一点点的清理
house for that kind of global information,
房子的全球信息,
So that's it for UIApplication,
UIApplication就是这样的,
Info,plist, we've already seen Info,plist,
plist信息,我们已经看到信息,plist,
Info,plist is really like a raw data file that's storing
信息,plist是真的喜欢原始数据文件的存储
a lot of your application's settings,
很多应用程序的设置,
We saw the one where we had HTTP URLs and
我们看到了一个HTTP url和
we want it to allow those unsecure ones,
我们想要让那些不安全的,
remember that the app transport security,
记住,应用交通安全,
We actually went and edited our Info,plist,
我们实际上和编辑信息,plist,
You can see it looks like this when you click on it,
你可以看到它是这样,当你点击它,
This is a property list editor right here,
这是一个属性列表编辑器,
So on the left hand side you're gonna have strings and
所以,在左手边你会有字符串和
dictionaries and arrays,
词典和数组,
Things that property lists are allowed to have,
属性列表允许的事情,
And on the right you're gonna have
右边你会有
the values that are in there,
的值,
This is really backing an XML file,
这真的是一个XML文件支持,
this property list that stores an XML file,
这个属性列表存储XML文件,
You can actually right-click on it and
你可以右键点击它
edit it as an XML file,
编辑XML文件,
I strongly recommend against this because
我强烈建议反对这样做,因为
you can break this so easily,
你可以轻易打破这种,
And then now the app won't be able to read this info,plist
然后现在应用程序无法读取信息,plist
anymore, so I recommend against doing that,
了,所以我不建议这样做,
But usually all these settings,
但通常这些设置,
you edit them in the project settings, right,
你编辑的项目设置,
You're not going to the Info,plist,
你不会信息,plist,
But it doesn't happen to be one or
但它不会发生一个或
at least I've never found one for that app transport
至少我从来没有发现一个用于应用程序传输
security, but maybe they want it intentionally obscure
安全,但也许他们想要故意模糊
because they want your app to be secure in that way,
因为他们想让你的应用程序是安全的,
But you've seen many, many settings here,
但是你看过很多设置,
like do we allow a portrait upside down, and
像我们允许肖像颠倒,
things like that, these are all stored in the Info,plist,
类似这样的事情,这些都是存储在信息,plist,
So this settings UI that you see is pretty much
这设置界面,你看到的是差不多
an editor also on Info,plist for
同样在信息,编辑plist
a lot of the things that you see there,
你看到的很多东西,
Another thing that you'll see in your settings
另一件事,你将看到在你的设置
are capabilities,
功能,
They're a number of features,
他们的特性,
couple dozen maybe, that require an external server,
几个可能,需要一个外部服务器,
Some external resource like iCloud or
像iCloud和一些外部资源
like CloudKit, requires some server that's storing all that
像CloudKit一样,需要一些服务器的存储
data out there or Game Center,
数据或游戏中心,
Is has all the servers so people can get together and
是所有服务器已经使人们可以聚在一起吗
play games and things like that,
玩游戏之类的,
When you have that kind of thing where you essentially
当你有这样的事情,你
need your app to be authenticated so
需要你的应用验证
that it it the server you're talking to knows it's you,
它的服务器你说知道是你,
Then you're going to have to go to the capabilities tab in
然后你要去的功能选项卡
the project settings and turn it on,
项目设置,打开它,
And turning it on, basically means update my entitlements
并把它,基本上意味着更新我的权利
so that I'm entitled to do this particular thing,
所以我有权做这个事情,
So, see some of the examples up there besides iCloud and
所以,看到一些例子除了iCloud和
Game Center at the top, you have Apple Pay,
游戏中心顶部,苹果支付,
In App Purchases, obviously these things require servers
在应用程序购买,显然这些事情需要服务器
and people connecting to them and things,
和人们连接到他们的事情,
Even the background fetching modes and
甚至和后台抓取模式
things like that require some entitlement if you're gonna be
比如,如果你要,需要一些权利
doing fetching while in the background,
在后台做抓取时,
So, check these out, this is a cool thing just to see what
所以,看看这些,这仅仅是一件很酷的事情,看看
features there are out there,
功能有,
Again, maybe way to get add some breadth,
再次,也许方法添加一些宽度,
some of them are not that difficult to implement,
他们中的一些人并不那么难以实现,
simple versions of anyway,
简单的版本,
But, you have to turn these on just to enable them,
但是,你必须把这些使他们,
My last topic here today is persistence,
今天我最后一次主题是坚持,
So persistence just means making data stay on the disk
所以持久性就意味着保持磁盘上的数据
when after your app is killed or dies,
当应用程序被杀或死后,
You already know about two really important ones,
你已经知道两个非常重要的,
User defaults which is tiny little pieces of data,
用户默认这是小块的数据,
preferences kind of data,
偏好类型的数据,
And has to be in PropertyLIst format,
并在PropertyLIst格式,
And then there's Core Data, which is kind of the opposite,
然后还有核心数据,这是相反的,
Monster relational database can have huge data in there,
怪物关系数据库可以有巨大的数据,
It's really for a data centric applications,
真的是对于以数据为中心的应用程序,
applications where the data is what is all about,
应用程序的数据是什么,
So, I'm not gonna talk about those,
所以,我不会谈论这些,
You know about those,
你知道这些,
I'm going to talk about these last three briefly,
我要去年三个简要谈论这些,
Archiving,
存档、
So archiving is a way of storing an object graph that
所以归档存储一个对象图的一种方式
is not a property list on disk,
不是一个磁盘上的属性列表,
Your storyboard is archived,
你的故事板存档,
Take all those views archives them to disk,
把所有那些观点档案到磁盘,
So, I talked about that,
所以,我讲过,
SQLite, we all know what SQL is,
SQLite,我们都知道SQL是什么,
its relation on database technology,
对数据库技术的关系,
iOS comes with kind of a light version of SQL at which
iOS带有一种光的版本的SQL
you don't usually ever use cuz you're using Core Data,
你通常不使用因为你使用核心数据,
Core Data's actually built on top of SQLite which
核心数据之上的SQLite
you don't have to access SQL directly,
你不需要直接访问SQL,
And finally, you can make things persist by
最后,你可以坚持的东西
putting them in the Unix file system,
让他们在Unix文件系统,
iOS, put Unix underneath, so
iOS,Unix下
you can put things in that file system,
你可以把东西放在文件系统,
We'll talk about how to do that,
我们将谈论如何做,
So, let's talk about archiving thing,
所以,让我们来谈谈存档,
Do not get the idea that this is a good way to
不懂的,这是一个好方法
have an arbitrary object graph that you have, and
你有任意对象图,
store it on disc,
存储盘,
Because archiving requires the involvement
因为归档要求参与
of all the objects that want to be archived,
所有的对象,想要存档,
Each of them has to implement these two methods up here
每个人都必须实现这两个方法
in code which essentially takes your object and
在本质上需要你的对象和代码
converts it into a dictionary,
将它转换成一个词典,
Not quite that, but that's 90% of what it is,
不,但这是90%的,
So converts to dictionary,
所以转换字典,
And then it also has to implement this initializer,
然后它还必须实现这个初始化,
any object that wants to be archived has to implement
任何对象,想要存档必须实现
this initializer,
这个初始化,
Which essentially gives you back that dictionary and
这给字典和你回来吗
tells you to create your objects from it,
告诉您创建对象,
Now this is kind of special,
这是特殊的,
this mechanism because the system is smart enough to
这种机制,因为系统足够聪明
know when you put an object in your dictionary,
知道当你把一个对象在你的字典,
And someone else in the same object graph
和别人在同一对象图
puts that object in there if that's the same object,
将该对象如果是同一个对象,
So it's not gonna ask that object to reconstitute itself
所以它不会要求对象重组本身
twice it's only gonna ask to do it once and
它只要求做一次两次
then it's gonna make pointers to it,
那么它会使指针,
So this is how the storyboard can work, if you think about
这就是故事板可以工作,如果你想
the storyboard, it's got a view hierarchy,
故事板,它有一个视图层次结构,
All those views are pointing to other views in their
所有这些观点是指向其他视图的
subviews but
子视图,但
they're also pointing back to their superviews,
他们也指出回到他们的父视图,
And obviously you only want one copy of every view in
很明显,你只想要一份每个视图
that hierarchy,
层次结构,
So UI view implements this coding protocol that has this
所以这个用户界面视图实现这个编码协议
methods in it,
方法,
And that's why view can be archived and all the sub cost
这就是为什么视图可以存档,所有子成本
of UI view that come with iOS like label and
的用户界面视图,像标签和iOS
button they also implement this,
他们也实现这个按钮,
And that's why the storyboard could be archived,
这就是为什么故事板可以存档,
But in the end if you start having an arbitrary
但到最后如果你开始拥有一个任意的
you try to implement this in code and UI for all of thems,
你想在代码中实现这个和UI主题,
object graph, and
对象图,
It starts to be more work than for example, just
例如,它开始被更多的工作比而已
making a core data database, to store that data in,
核心数据的数据库,存储数据,
Or converting it to a property list and
或将它转换为一个属性列表
using user defaults if it's a small thing,
使用用户违约,如果它是一个小的事情,
So this people here listen and they're like, that's cool,
这人听,他们就像,很酷,
yeah I've got a big object graph of data and
是的我有一个巨大的数据和对象图
I'm just gonna put it on this using this,
我要把它放在这用这个,
Well it's a little more involved than you might think,
这是更比你想象的,
And it also, you have to know what you're doing here to make
同时,你必须知道你在做什么在这里
sure you get those back pointers properly set up and
确保你拿回这些指针正确设置和
things like that,
类似这样的事情,
SQLite, so this is SQL in a single file,
SQLite,所以这是一个SQL文件,
one gigantic file the entire SQL database,
一个巨大的文件整个SQL数据库,
It's not a network thing it's purely just a local file,
它不是一个网络的事情纯粹只是一个本地文件,
SQLite is an Open Source project, comes with iOS,
SQLite是一个开源项目,iOS,
It's not really good for everything,
这不是很好的,
I wouldn't store huge things in there,
我不会储存巨大的事情,
It's not really built for
这不是真的了
that I'll probably put huge things in the file system,
我可能会把巨大的东西在文件系统中,
Even core data when you create something big like
当你创造一些大甚至核心数据
attribute NSData there's a switch in there,
属性NSData有一个开关,
You can turn on which is store this in the external file not
您可以打开存储在外部文件
actually in the data base,
实际的数据基础,
And that's usually worth filling if the object is gonna
而这通常是值得如果对象是要填充
be fairly large,
是相当大的,
The API to use in SQLite directly looks like c,
API直接使用SQLite看起来像c,
Not surprisingly it's not object oriented in any way
毫不奇怪它不是面向对象的
it's just classic single SQL call there's functions that
只是典型的单一SQL调用的函数
you pass SQL language to basically,
你基本上通过SQL语言,
And it executes it and even though core data uses it you
它执行,即使核心数据使用它
don't see it from core data directly,
不要直接看到它从核心数据,
You know, there's a new probably use SQL is
你知道,有一个新的可能使用SQL
if you had some existing database or something,
如果你有一些现有的数据库,
The file system,
文件系统,
now the file system is something that I would imagine
现在是我想象的文件系统上
some of you might want to use in your final project,
你们中的一些人可能想要使用在你最后的项目中,
And your access to the Unix filesystem that underlies
和你的Unix文件系统的访问
your application is a little bit limited,
您的应用程序是有限的一点,
And so the way that you access it is generally be used four
所以,你通常使用四个访问它
steps,
步骤,
First you're gonna get a URL into the Unix filesystem and
首先你会得到一个URL到Unix文件系统
there are about 20 preset points
大约有20个预置点
in the Unix filesystem that you can get a URL to,
你可以得到一个URL的Unix文件系统,
And once you've got that URL,
一旦你理解了这个网址,
then you can create directories there,
然后您可以创建目录,
Create files there by taking your URL and adding path
创建文件的URL和添加路径
components to it to describe directories and files,
组件描述目录和文件,
Then you write to the files,
然后你写文件,
you're usually doing this with the data object,
你通常做这个数据对象,
Or there's some property lists methods that can write out
或者有一些属性列表的方法,可以写出来
to a file,
到一个文件中,
And then finally you're gonna manage all those files with
最后你要管理所有这些文件
a class called a file manager,
一个类称为一个文件管理器,
So the file manager lets you copy files and
文件管理器允许你复制文件和
remove files and list files and directories,
删除文件和文件和目录列表,
And all the things you can do with a file system,
和所有的事情你可以做一个文件系统,
you do with a file manager,
你做一个文件管理器,
So these are the main aspects of accessing the file system,
这是访问文件系统的主要方面,
So let's look at each of these things,
让我们看看这些东西,
It's a Unix filesystem it starts at root of course it's
这是一个Unix文件系统从根开始当然是
protected, there's permissions,
保护,有权限,
So you can't go writing files into system directories or
所以你不能写文件到系统目录或去
even reading a lot of the system directories,
即使阅读很多系统的目录,
And you certainly can't see other apps
你当然不能看到其他应用程序
what they're doing over there,
他们在做什么,
That's completely off limits there,
完全禁止的,
In fact, you can only write and
事实上,你只能写信
read inside what's called your application's sandbox,
读所谓的内部应用程序的沙盒,
So sandbox is this totally segregated part of the file
这是沙盒完全隔离的文件的一部分
system,
系统,
do things,
做事情,
And now why do we have a sandbox?
现在为什么我们有一个沙盒?
It might seem obvious to you for some things,
有些东西,似乎明显的你了
For example security is a big one,
例如安全是一个大的,
We don't want other apps to be able to reach into your app
我们不想让其他应用程序可以进入你的应用
and damage you,
和伤害你,
That would be really bad,
这将是非常糟糕的,
So we gotta have security for that,
所以我们要有安全,
There's privacy, we wouldn't want those other apps to
有隐私,我们不想让其他应用程序
be able to look inside you and see your private data either,
能看在你和看到你的私人数据,
But another interesting reason that you wouldn't maybe
但也许你不会另一个有趣的原因
think of is clean up,
认为的清理,
If someone deletes your app from their phone entirely they
如果有人从他们的手机完全删除应用程序
want everything this app has ever created to be gone,
想要一切这个程序所创建的走了,
And by having the sandbox, and that's the only place you can
通过沙盒,这是唯一的地方
write, when you delete, it deletes your entire sandbox,
写,当你删除,删除整个沙盒,
So anything you've ever created is gone,
所以任何你曾经创建了,
So you don't have to worry about people writing
所以你不必担心人们写作
things into system directories and all of that,
到系统目录和所有的东西,
Which happens all over the place on the Mac for
这到处都发生在Mac上
example, you're home directory slash library has got
例子,你主目录削减图书馆了
all kinds of junk in there,
各种各样的垃圾,
They don't have the same concept there of everything
他们没有相同的概念的一切
being isolated like you have in iOS,
在iOS孤立的喜欢你,
So it's actually a cool feature have the sandbox,
这实际上是一个很酷的功能有沙箱,
Now inside the sandbox there are certain directories that
现在在沙箱有特定的目录
you can get URL too, I can says about 20 of them,
你可以得到URL,我能说大约20人,
So for example, there's the application directory
例如,应用程序目录
that's where your applications binary is,
这就是应用程序二进制文件,
You can only read and In there read only, you cannot write
你只能读和只读,你不能写
to your own application no self modifying code allowed,
到您自己的应用程序不允许自修改代码,
in IOS,
在IOS,
This is also where you might have things JPEG's or
这也是在JPEG或你可能有事情
other things if you don't use the image assets things,
其他东西如果你不使用资产的东西的图片,
You can actually just drag JPEG's or
你可以直接将JPEG或
whatever directory into your project,
任何目录到您的项目,
And they'll appear in you application bundle you
他们会出现在你的应用程序包
can look at the directly,
可以直接看,
We rarely do that, by the way,
我们很少做,顺便说一下,
But other URL's that you can look in there that
但是其他的网址,你可以看看
are kinda cool,
是有点酷,
There's the documents directory, that's a big one,
文件目录,这是一个大的,
That's where you're gonna put user created data
这就是你要把用户创建的数据
that the user cares about,
用户关心的,
What the user perceives as their documents,
用户感知的文档,
Even if you don't have a document oriented application
即使你没有一个面向文档的应用程序
the user considers that as like that's their data,
用户认为,这样的数据,
That's what they entered,
这是他们进入,
Now you're app might store that on the network,
现在你的应用程序可能会存储在网络上,
So maybe
所以也许
Or your app is just not the kind of app that has data like
或应用程序不是这样的应用程序数据
that, fine,
,很好,
But if it does the documents directory is
但如果它的文件目录
your primary place you're gonna store stuff,
你要存储的东西,你的主要地方
But sometimes the user creates things and
但有时用户创建的东西,
you're really just cashing it,
你真的只是兑现,
So for example,
举个例子,
let's go back to our Twitter client, Smashtag,
让我们回到我们的Twitter客户端,Smashtag,
In Smashtag we downloaded images and
在Smashtag我们图片和下载
maybe we wanted to keep the images that
也许我们想要的图像
were associated with the image tab local,
当地与图像相关的标签,
That way I'm local even
我甚至当地
though I'm not connected to the network,
虽然我没有连接到网络,
But those aren't really user data their just something I
但这些并不是真的只是我用户数据
wanna cache,
想要缓存,
I just want to keep them local so for ease of use,
我只是想让他们当地的易用性,
But as things go out of recent,
但作为最近的事情出去,
I'd probably clear them out,
我可能清晰,
And if that cache directory got completely cleared out it
如果缓存目录完全清除它
would be fine I'd just reload them all again,
会好我再重新加载它们,
So the caches directory is a place
因此,缓存目录是一个地方
to put stuff that you can easily get again,
再把东西可以很容易地得到,
Images and stuff that you're caching,
图片和东西你缓存,
And there's a bunch of other directories,
还有很多其他目录,
I don't have time to talk about all of them,
我没有时间谈论他们所有人,
unfortunately,
不幸的是,
So how do we get our URL to one of these special
那么,我们如何让我们的这些特殊的URL
directories like the document structure or
目录的文档结构
the caches directory, things like that?
缓存目录,类似这样的事情吗?
We're gonna use this another default,
我们将使用这个另一个默认的,
just like we had in in this notification center,default,
就像我们在通知中心,默认情况下,
Now we have FileManager,default,
现在我们有文件管理,默认情况下,
So the FileManager is the thing that lets you
文件管理是让你的东西
manage the entire file system, and
管理整个文件系统,
it has a default one that you can use,
它有一个默认的一个,您可以使用,
And it has a method called URLs for
它有一个名为url的方法
directory in domainMask, okay,
目录domainMask,好吧,
That's this method you see right here,
这个方法你看到这里,
And it gives you an array of URLs,
它给你一个url数组,
In iOS, there's only ever one URL in there,
在iOS,只能有一个URL,
The reason this is an array on desktop machines like the Mac,
之所以这是一个数组像Mac台式机,
sometimes you'll have like a library directory that has
有时,你会像一个图书馆目录
one for the user, one on the network so
一个用于用户,另一个在网络上
there's multiple of them,
有多种,
But in iOS all things are inside the sandbox so
但在iOS沙箱内都是如此
the only domain, that's why the user domain mask there is
唯一的领域,这就是为什么用户域的面具
user domain mask,
用户域的面具,
So there's only ever one URL,
所以只有一个URL,
So there's only one URL for your documents directory,
所以只有一个URL文档目录,
One URL for your caches directory,
一个URL缓存目录,
One URL for your documentation directory,
一个URL为你的文档目录,
One URL for your application, okay, just one,
一个URL为您的应用程序,只有一个,
Just the one in the sandbox,
只是一个沙箱中
So you specify which directory you want with that
所以你指定目录
argument therefore directory,
因此参数目录,
And that has to be a type
这是一个类型
FileManager,SearchPathDirect- ory,
SearchPathDirect文件管理——理论、
So again, look that up in the documentation and
所以,看在文档和
you'll see the various directories in your sandbox
你会看到各种目录沙箱中
that you can look at,
你可以看看,
There's about 20 of them,
大约有20人,
And if you are the document director for example,
如果你是文档总监为例,
you say ,documentDirectory right there,
你说,documentDirectory,
And it will give you back an array where there is only one
,它会给你一个数组只有一个
thing in there,
在那里,
document directory in your sandbox,
在你的沙箱文档目录,
Make sense?
有意义吗?
So that's how we get in,
这就是我们,
Once we get in, we want to create directories in there,
一旦我们得到,我们要创建目录,
create files, whatever,
创建文件,无论如何,
We, or access files,
我们,或访问文件,
We do those by using these appending methods in URL,
我们做这些URL,通过使用这些附加方法
So we have that URL and we send a message to the URL,
所以我们有URL发送消息到一个网址,
Like give me a new URL by URL appendingPathComponent
像给我一个新的URL appendingPathComponent通过URL
whatever the name of my directory or the name of
无论我目录的名字或名称
the file that I want or by appending path extension, so
我想要的文件,或通过添加路径扩展,所以
,jpeg, or something like that, so I can get my jpeg file,
、jpeg或类似的东西,所以我可以得到我的jpeg文件,
So by doing that I build a path, the URL,
我建立一个路径,通过URL,
to the file I want,
我想要到文件,
So that's how I navigate around in my sand box,
这就是我在砂箱,浏览
So now I have the URL and
所以现在我有URL和
I can do a lot of things with that URL,
我可以做很多事情,网址,
I'll show you in a moment how you can write files out and
我将向您展示如何编写文件,
things like that but you can also find out about things URL
之类的东西,但你也可以了解事情的URL
like is this a file?
像这一个文件吗?
Or is it a directory?
还是一个目录?
Or is it on the network for example?
比如还是网络上的吗?
Cuz you have a URL that someone gives you,
因为你有一个URL,有人给你,
maybe it's a network URL,
也许这是一个网络网址,
Http, colon, slash, slash, something,
Http、结肠削减,削减,东西,
Well that's not a file URL so is file, file URL right there,
这不是一个文件URL所以文件,文件的URL,
we tell you that it's in the file system,
我们告诉你,这是在文件系统中,
A really powerful method in URL is resourceValues for
一个真正强大的方法在URL是resourceValues
keys,
键,
So resource values for keys you give it an array of keys
所以资源值键你给它一个数组的键
that are attributes of files,
文件的属性,
these keys are attributes of files, like the files size, or
这些键的属性文件,文件大小,或
the files creation date, or whatever,
文件创建日期,等等,
And it will return you a dictionary with those keys and
它会返回你与钥匙和一本字典
the values for the file, for
文件,的值
the URL that you're pointing to,
你指向的URL,
So that's how you can find out the size of the file,
这就是你可以找到的文件的大小,
where the creationDate or whether isDirectory,
创建日期或者是否isDirectory,
Things like that,
类似这样的事情,
Notice the listing throws so be careful here,
注意这里的清单把所以要小心,
You have to do this in a try,
你要做这个尝试,
How about writing files out to the file system,
如何写文件到文件系统,
Well mostly we do this with a data,
我们主要做这个数据,
If you have for example a UI image and
如果你有例如UI和形象
you wanna store on your screen, or
你想要存储在你的屏幕上,或
whatever that you downloaded from the internet, and
无论你从互联网上下载
you wanna store that into the file system,
你想要存储到文件系统中,
there's actually a cool function called, I think,
有一个很酷的功能,我认为,
UI image jpeg representation or something like that,
UI图像jpeg代表之类的,
And you give it a UI image, and it will return a data,
你给它一个UI的形象,它将返回一个数据,
And a data will have the data of the jpeg image,
和数据将jpeg图像的数据,
That you can store,
你可以存储,
And then you can say write to url,
然后你可以说写网址,
So this is a data method here write to URL atomically,
这是一个URL自动数据方法编写,
And then we'll write it out to that URL,
然后我们会把它写出来,网址,
So you have to build yourself URL like get in the sandbox
所以你必须建立自己的URL像沙箱
directory, and then depending whatever name you want to it,
目录,然后根据任何你想要的名字,
Then you say write to URL, atomically just means it'll
然后你说写网址,自动就意味着它会
safely, it'll write it to a temp file first and
安全,它会先到一个临时文件,写下来
then swap it in so if you ran out of disk space
然后交换在如果你耗尽磁盘空间
while writing it or something it wouldn't corrupt if a file
在写什么的不会腐败的如果一个文件
that was already there for example,
这已经为例,
Now, to get the data object back you just use the same
现在,你只是使用相同的数据对象
initializer you used when we did some hashtag or
初始化你当我们做了一些标签或使用
the lecture before that,
演讲之前,
what we said data init, contents of URL,
我们说,数据初始化,URL的内容,
Now in that case,
现在在这种情况下,
if the URL was a network URL and it blocked the main queue,
如果URL是一个URL和网络封锁了主要队列,
here that URL could be a file system URL,
URL可以是一个文件系统URL,
And it wouldn't block the main queue,
它不会阻止主队列,
Loading files up super fast,
加载文件非常快,
So you don't really need to do that in a separate
你真的不需要这样做在一个单独的
thread unless maybe it was a gigantic file,
线程,除非可能是一个巨大的文件,
But even then, maybe you could do that, yeah question,
但即使这样,也许你可以这样做,是的问题,
When would you not wanna do atomically right here?
当你不会想做自动呢?
It's hard for me to even think of an example with that,
甚至对我来说很难想到的一个例子,
Maybe it's a really huge file and
也许这是一个非常巨大的文件
you don't wanna create two copies of it,
你不想创建两个副本,
The safe copy and then over, and so
安全的副本,然后结束,所以
you've got an existing copy of a huge file, let's say,
你有现有的复制一个巨大的文件,比方说,
And you don't wanna create another copy of it
你不想创建另一个副本
as a safe copy before you move it in, so,
作为安全复制在你移动,所以,
that you might say atomically no so,
你可能说自动不如此,
it just destroys your old one right off of that, I mean,
它只是破坏你的旧的,我的意思是,
I'm really stretching to think of good example,
我真的拉伸的很好的例子,
you almost always want true to there,
你总是想要真实,
So, that's how you read and write files with data,
这就是你如何读取和写入文件的数据,
very common way to do that,
很常见的方法,
Once you've written out files, you want to be able to go
一旦写入文件,你希望能够去
through your file system and like look at what files are in
通过你的文件系统,并像看看文件
certain directories or things like that,
某些目录或类似的东西,
Maybe you've got caches out there and
也许你已经有了和缓存
you want to see what's in your cache or whatever,
你想看看你的缓存之类的,
And that's what FileManager's for,
这就是文件管理的,
It has dozens of methods for doing that like,
这有许多方法来做,
createDirectory( at url, which will create a directory for
createDirectory(url,这将创建一个目录
you so you can put files in there,
你在那里,你可以把文件
And it also has a bunch, it has a delegate,
它也有很多,它有一个委托,
And a bunch of shoulds,
和一群应该,
Should I allow creating this file?
我应该允许创建这个文件吗?
Things like that,
类似这样的事情,
The FileManager by the way is thread safe in the same way
文件管理的方法是线程安全的方式都是一样的
that an NSManagedObjectContext is thread safe,
一个NSManagedObjectContext是线程安全的,
In other words, if you create the FileManager on a certain
换句话说,如果您创建特定的文件管理
thread then it's always thread safe to use it in that thread,
线程就总是在线程,线程安全的使用它
in that same queue,
在同一队列,
If you create a FileManager on a different one,
如果您创建了一个在另一个文件管理,
that one's safe to use in its queue and
一个队列和安全使用
they will work together as well,
他们将在一起工作,
Just don't try to use a FileManager created in one
只是不要尝试使用在一个创建的文件管理
thread over on a different thread,
线程在一个不同的线程,
That is not thread safe,
这不是线程安全的,
It's just like how NSManagedObjectContext is
就像NSManagedObjectContext
thread safe,
线程安全的,
That is it for this lecture so the coming up we have
这是这节课我们的到来
is accessibility is our next lecture on Monday and
可访问性是星期一,我们下一节课吗
also your slides are due for the alternate final there,
还你的幻灯片将替代最后那里,
Do not forget that,
不要忘记,
I put it in red,
我把它放在红色,
How many people,
有多少人,
A few of you, so make sure you get your slides in,
的你,所以确保你得到你的幻灯片,
Wednesday will be the alternate final itself,
周三将会替代最终本身,
Your final project is due the Sunday after that,
最终项目定于周日之后,
the Sunday the 19th of March, at midnight,
在午夜,周日3月19
That is it,
这是它,
I will see you all on Monday,
周一我将看到你所有,
>> For more please visit us at www,stanford,edu
> >更多信息请访问我们在www,斯坦福大学,埃杜